上菜了
Order up!
根据真实故事改编
大创业家
深影字幕组
原创译制
我知道你在想什么
I know what you're thinking.
shinY
"我要五个轴的搅拌机有什么用
"What the heck do I need a five spindle for,
我卖的奶昔
when I barely sell enough milkshakes
连单轴搅拌机的本钱都赚不回来" 对吧
to justify my single spindle?" Right?
大错特错
Wrong.
你对是先有鸡还是先有蛋这个观点熟悉吗
Are you familiar with the notion of the chicken or the egg,
格里菲斯先生 我之所以提这个是因为
Mr. Griffith? I mention it because,
我觉得这个观点可以应用在这里
well, I think it applies here.
你是因为没有卖出足够多的奶昔
Do you not need the multi-mixer because,
才不需要多轴搅拌机呢
well heck, you're not selling enough milkshakes?
还是因为没有多轴搅拌机
Or are you not selling enough milkshakes
才没能卖出足够多的奶昔呢
because you don't have a multi-mixer?
我坚信是后者
I firmly believe it's the latter.
你看 当你的客人走进来后
You see your customer comes in here
他知道要是在你的商店里买奶昔的话
and he knows if he orders a shake from your establishment,
肯定要等很久
he's in for a terrific wait.
他之前就苦等过好久 所以他会对自己说
He's done it before and he thinks to himself,
"天 这个错误我可绝对不会犯第二次"
"Well by-golly, I'm not going to make that mistake again."
但如果你有品食魁首牌有直驱电机专利的
But if you had the Prince Castle five spindle multi-mixer
五轴搅拌机
with patented direct-drive electric motor,
你制作出美味可口 覆满冰霜的奶昔的速度
well you greatly increase your ability to produce delicious,
会加快很多很多
frosty milkshakes fast.
记住我的话 绝对完爆你现在的机器
Mark my words, dollars to doughnuts,
你卖出的奶昔量
you'll be selling more of those sons-a-bitches
会数都数不过来的
than you can shake a stick at.
设备升级了 需求也会水涨船高
You increase the supply, and the demand will follow.
设备升级 需求上涨
Increase supply, demand follows.
就像鸡和蛋的关系 你跟上我的思路了吗
Chicken-egg. Do you follow my logic?
你肯定跟上了 因为你是个有前瞻思想的人
I know you do, because you're a bright forward-thinking guy
听到一个好主意时 立刻就能够分辨出来
who knows a good idea when he hears one.
所以 你意如何
So, whaddaya say?
不要 但还是要谢谢你
Nah, but thanks anyways.
上菜
Order's up.
1954年 密苏里州 圣路易斯市
小姐 还要多久
Miss? How much longer?
再等几分钟
Should be a few more minutes.
你二十分钟前也是这么说的
You said that 20 minutes ago.
很抱歉 但我们今天真的很忙
I'm so sorry, we're really busy today.
距贝尔维尔还有27英里
你看 老兄 这是显而易见的
See, it only stands to reason here, bud,
升级设备 需求就会上涨
if you increase supply, demand will follow.
就像鸡和蛋的关系 你跟上我的思路了吗
Chicken and the egg. Do you follow my logic?
你肯定跟上了 因为你是个有前瞻思想的人
Of course you do, you're a bright forward-thinking guy
听到一个好主意时 立刻就能够分辨出来
who knows a good idea when he hears one.
所以
So?
你意如何
What do you say?
powered by SHINY PHAROS
可算来了
Here we go.
- 这是啥啊 - 请慢用
- What is...? - Enjoy.
我点的是炭烧牛排
I ordered the barbeque beef!
有很多好的先例 非常厉害的先例
There's a lot of good leads, real-real strong leads.
是啊 怎么了
Yeah. What?
没什么 那很好啊
Nothing. That's wonderful.
我是说 他们都有浓厚的兴趣
Well, I mean, there's just tremendous interest.
我确信有的
I'm sure there is.
你听起来像是不相信我
You sound like you don't believe me.
当然不会了 雷 我为什么会不相信你呢
Of course, Ray. Why wouldn't I?
好了 我这里还有很多文书工作要做
Alright. I've got a lot of paperwork to do here.
所以 我明天在路上再给你打
So ahh... I'll... I'll call you from the road tomorrow.
好的
Okay.
好了 晚安
Alright. Goodnight.
积极的力量
坚持
Persistence.
世上没有什么能够替代坚持
Nothing in the world can take the place of persistence.
才能不能 有才能的
Talent won't; Nothing is more common
不成功人士随处可见
than unsuccessful men with talent.
天赋不能 徒劳无获的天才并不少见
Genius won't; Unrewarded genius is practically a cliché.
教育不能 世上无处不行走着受过教育的白痴
Education won't; The world is full of educated fools.
只有坚持和果断才是力量之源
Persistence and determination alone are all powerful.
要展现出你不会被任何事情打败
Show that you don't have to be defeated by anything.
要如明镜止水 提升健康状态
That you can have peace of mind, improved health
要有取之不竭的力量
and a never ceasing flow of energy.
如果你每天都努力去达成上述条件
If you attempt each and every day to achieve these things,
最终它们会深植于你的身体之中
the results will make themselves obvious to you.
尽管这听起来可能像是魔法般的概念
While it may sound like a magical notion,
但只有你才能造就你的未来
it is in you to create your own future.
我这一代人最伟大的发现就是
The greatest discovery of my generation
人类可以通过改变思想态度
is that human beings can alter their lives
来改变人生
by altering their attitudes of mind.
美国思想家
或如拉尔夫·沃尔多·爱默生所说
Or as Ralph Waldo Emerson declared,
"一个人整天想着什么 他就是什么样子的"
"A man is what he thinks about all day long."
距切斯特菲尔德还有5英里
品食魁首销售公司 有什么可以帮您的吗
Prince Castle Sales, how can I help you?
- 你好 朱恩 - 雷 你那边怎么样了
- Hi, June. - Ray, how's it going down there?
好极了 赚了不少
Good, swell, lot of interest.
等一下 我来看看给你的留言
Hold on, let me fetch your messages.
联合铝业的吉恩·拉弗蒂
Let's see, Gene Rafferty from United Aluminum
需要改期到周五
needs to reschedule Friday.
艾德·南斯来电问询了退款的事宜
Ed Nance calling about the refund.
斯旺父子店又打了一次电话
Swan and Sons, they called again,
我们已经拖欠六十天了
we're sixty days past due.
还有畸形儿基金会的一位女士 对了
A lady from the March of Dimes, oh...
我们有一个订单 六个搅拌机
We got an order, six mixers.
- 六个 - 是的
- Six? - Mm-hmm.
加利福尼亚州的一个汽车餐馆
Some drive-in out in California.
同一个地方 不 那不可能的
Same place, one place. No that's... that's impossible.
- 我记下来了 - 我敢肯定你是搞错了
- I've got the slip right here. - No, I'm sure you misunderstood.
这样吧 你把电话号码给我
You know what? Give me the number.
- 你有笔吗 - 好的
- You got a pen? - Okay.
好了
Alright.
- 你好 麦当劳 - 你好 下午好
- Hello, McDonald's. - Hello, good afternoon.
我可以和店主讲话吗
May I please speak with the owner.
- 哪一个 - 什么意思
- Which one? - I'm sorry?
迪克还是麦克
Dick or Mac?
只要有空 哪一个都行
Ahh, whichever one's available, I guess.
上菜 我要六份炸薯条
Order up! I need six fries!
- 小馅饼好了 - 我是迪克
- Patties up! - This is Dick.
你好 迪克
Hello, Dick,
我是品食魁首销售公司的雷·克洛克
this is Ray Kroc from Prince Castle Sales.
我之所以来电是因为有人下了订单
The reason I'm calling is someone placed an order...
是的 是的 就是我下的
Yes. Yes, that was me.
你多快能把它们送过来
How soon can you get them out here?
这也是我打电话的原因 迪克
Well, that's actually why I'm phoning now, Dick.
我想可能是传达有误...
I think there might have been some kind of miscommunication...
在冷冻室 最上面架子的左边 抱歉
Freezer! Top shelf! Left side! Sorry.
没关系
No problem.
我的秘书记得你是要六个
My secretary's under the impression that you wanted six?
是啊 我觉得那是个错误
Yeah, you know, I think that was a mistake.
是啊 我也是那么想的 什么样的汽车餐馆
Well, that's what I figured. I mean, what kind of drive-in
会同时需要做三十杯奶昔啊
can make 30 milkshakes at a time.
还是来八个吧 怎么了 阿尔
Better make it eight. What's that, Al?
有个新盒子... 现在真的很忙
There's a brand new box... Look, now isn't the best time.
是啊 我很抱歉 我理解 我还有个小问...
Yeah, I'm sorry. I understand. I'm still a little bit...
你知道送到哪吧 加利福尼亚州圣贝纳迪诺市
You know where to send them? San Bernardino, California.
- 好的 - 十四街与E街拐角处
- Yeah. - Corner of 14th and E.
稍等一下 有详细收货人吗
Hold on a minute. To anyone in particular?
写店名就好了 麦当劳 好了吗 非常感谢
Just the store is fine. McDonald's. Okay. Thanks a lot.
好的
Yeah.
密苏里州 44号公路
亚利桑那州 66号公路
圣贝纳迪诺市城界
加利福尼亚州
66号公路
圣贝纳迪诺市城界
加利福尼亚州
66号公路
圣贝纳迪诺市城界
加利福尼亚州
66号公路
圣贝纳迪诺市城界
加利福尼亚州
66号公路
圣贝纳迪诺市城界
加利福尼亚州
66号公路
圣贝纳迪诺市城界
加利福尼亚州
66号公路
圣贝纳迪诺市城界
加利福尼亚州
66号公路
圣贝纳迪诺市城界
加利福尼亚州
66号公路
圣贝纳迪诺市城界
加利福尼亚州
66号公路
圣贝纳迪诺市城界
加利福尼亚州
66号公路
圣贝纳迪诺市城界
加利福尼亚州
66号公路
圣贝纳迪诺市城界
加利福尼亚州
66号公路
圣贝纳迪诺市城界
加利福尼亚州
66号公路
圣贝纳迪诺市城界
加利福尼亚州
66号公路
圣贝纳迪诺市城界
加利福尼亚州
66号公路
圣贝纳迪诺市城界
加利福尼亚州
66号公路
圣贝纳迪诺市城界
加利福尼亚州
66号公路
圣贝纳迪诺市城界
加利福尼亚州
66号公路
圣贝纳迪诺市城界
加利福尼亚州
66号公路
圣贝纳迪诺市城界
加利福尼亚州
66号公路
圣贝纳迪诺市城界
加利福尼亚州
66号公路
圣贝纳迪诺市城界
加利福尼亚州
66号公路
圣贝纳迪诺市城界
加利福尼亚州
66号公路
圣贝纳迪诺市城界
加利福尼亚州
66号公路
圣贝纳迪诺市城界
加利福尼亚州
66号公路
圣贝纳迪诺市城界
加利福尼亚州
66号公路
圣贝纳迪诺市城界
加利福尼亚州
66号公路
圣贝纳迪诺市城界
加利福尼亚州
66号公路
圣贝纳迪诺市城界
加利福尼亚州
66号公路
圣贝纳迪诺市城界
加利福尼亚州
66号公路
圣贝纳迪诺市城界
加利福尼亚州
66号公路
圣贝纳迪诺市城界
加利福尼亚州
66号公路
圣贝纳迪诺市城界
加利福尼亚州
66号公路
圣贝纳迪诺市城界
加利福尼亚州
66号公路
圣贝纳迪诺市城界
加利福尼亚州
66号公路
圣贝纳迪诺市城界
加利福尼亚州
66号公路
圣贝纳迪诺市城界
加利福尼亚州
66号公路
圣贝纳迪诺市城界
加利福尼亚州
66号公路
圣贝纳迪诺市城界
加利福尼亚州
66号公路
圣贝纳迪诺市城界
加利福尼亚州
66号公路
圣贝纳迪诺市城界
加利福尼亚州
66号公路
圣贝纳迪诺市城界
加利福尼亚州
66号公路
圣贝纳迪诺市城界
加利福尼亚州
66号公路
圣贝纳迪诺市城界
加利福尼亚州
66号公路
圣贝纳迪诺市城界
加利福尼亚州
66号公路
圣贝纳迪诺市城界
加利福尼亚州
66号公路
圣贝纳迪诺市城界
加利福尼亚州
66号公路
圣贝纳迪诺市城界
加利福尼亚州
66号公路
圣贝纳迪诺市城界
加利福尼亚州
66号公路
圣贝纳迪诺市城界
加利福尼亚州
66号公路
圣贝纳迪诺市城界
加利福尼亚州
66号公路
圣贝纳迪诺市城界
加利福尼亚州
66号公路
圣贝纳迪诺市城界
加利福尼亚州
66号公路
圣贝纳迪诺市城界
加利福尼亚州
66号公路
圣贝纳迪诺市城界
加利福尼亚州
66号公路
圣贝纳迪诺市城界
加利福尼亚州
66号公路
圣贝纳迪诺市城界
加利福尼亚州
66号公路
圣贝纳迪诺市城界
加利福尼亚州
66号公路
圣贝纳迪诺市城界
加利福尼亚州
66号公路
圣贝纳迪诺市城界
加利福尼亚州
66号公路
圣贝纳迪诺市城界
加利福尼亚州
66号公路
圣贝纳迪诺市城界
加利福尼亚州
66号公路
麦当劳汉堡
别担心 排队很快的
Don't worry, it moves fast.
真的吗
Really?
麦当劳是行业第一
我们只使用经美国政府检验过的牛肉
祝你们有愉快的一天
You guys have a great day.
你好 欢迎光临麦当劳 您要点什么
Hi, welcome to McDonald's. May I take your order?
好的 给我来一个汉堡
Yeah, give me a hamburger,
一份薯条和一杯可口可乐
French fries and a Coca-Cola.
- 总共35美分 谢谢 - 好的
- That'll be .35 cents, please. - Alright.
找您15美分零钱
Fifteen cents is your change.
给您
Here you are.
- 这是什么 - 您点的食物啊
- What's this? - Your food.
不不不 我才刚点
No, no, no. I just ordered.
现在已经好了
And now it's here.
你确定吗
You sure?
好吧
Alright.
那个...
Where are the umm...
餐具和盘子之类的在哪里
You know, the silverware and plates and everything?
从包装袋里面直接拿出来吃掉
You just eat it straight out of the wrapper,
然后一起扔掉就好了
then you throw it all out.
好吧
Alright.
真的吗
Really?
好的
Okay.
我该在哪吃呢
Where do I eat it?
在您的车里啊
In your car.
公园啊
At the park.
回家啊 您想在哪吃都行
At home. Wherever you'd like.
好的 好的 好的 谢谢你
Okay. Okay. Okay, thanks.
- 我们可以和您一起吃吗 - 好 没问题
- May we join you? - Huh? Yeah. Sure.
谢谢
Thank you.
扔在这里就行 我来把它扫走
Just throw it right there and I'll sweep it up.
一切都满意吗
How is everything?
这可能是我这辈子吃过的最好吃的汉堡了
This might be the best hamburger I've ever had in my life.
让您满意就是我们的目标
Well, we aim to please.
我是麦当劳里面的那个"麦"
Mac McDonald.
这么回事啊 你看这个 我是雷·克洛克
Oh! Well, look at this... Ray Kroc.
卖多轴搅拌机的人 你和我弟弟迪克通过电话
The multi-mixer fella. You spoke with my brother, Dick.
雷·克洛克
销售部长
品食魁首销售公司
雷·克洛克
销售部长
品食魁首销售公司
雷·克洛克
销售部长
品食魁首销售公司
雷·克洛克
销售部长
品食魁首销售公司
雷·克洛克
销售部长
品食魁首销售公司
雷·克洛克
销售部长
品食魁首销售公司
雷·克洛克
销售部长
品食魁首销售公司
雷·克洛克
销售部长
品食魁首销售公司
雷·克洛克
销售部长
品食魁首销售公司
雷·克洛克
销售部长
品食魁首销售公司
雷·克洛克
销售部长
品食魁首销售公司
雷·克洛克
销售部长
品食魁首销售公司
雷·克洛克
销售部长
品食魁首销售公司
雷·克洛克
销售部长
品食魁首销售公司
雷·克洛克
销售部长
品食魁首销售公司
雷·克洛克
销售部长
品食魁首销售公司
雷·克洛克
销售部长
品食魁首销售公司
雷·克洛克
销售部长
品食魁首销售公司
雷·克洛克
销售部长
品食魁首销售公司
雷·克洛克
销售部长
品食魁首销售公司
雷·克洛克
销售部长
品食魁首销售公司
雷·克洛克
销售部长
品食魁首销售公司
雷·克洛克
销售部长
品食魁首销售公司
雷·克洛克
销售部长
品食魁首销售公司
雷·克洛克
销售部长
品食魁首销售公司
雷·克洛克
销售部长
品食魁首销售公司
雷·克洛克
销售部长
品食魁首销售公司
雷·克洛克
销售部长
品食魁首销售公司
雷·克洛克
销售部长
品食魁首销售公司
雷·克洛克
销售部长
品食魁首销售公司
雷·克洛克
销售部长
品食魁首销售公司
雷·克洛克
销售部长
品食魁首销售公司
雷·克洛克
销售部长
品食魁首销售公司
雷·克洛克
销售部长
品食魁首销售公司
雷·克洛克
销售部长
品食魁首销售公司
雷·克洛克
销售部长
品食魁首销售公司
雷·克洛克
销售部长
品食魁首销售公司
正是我
I did yeah, yeah.
你在这外面做什么
What are you doing way out here?
我之前正在洛杉矶谈生意
I'm in Los Angeles, business meetings.
我就想既然我都来这里了
I thought I'm in the neighborhood,
何不如过来打个招呼呢
I should just swing by and say hello.
我很高兴你来了
Well, I'm sure glad you did.
这一切 经营得真是棒极了
This whole thing. This is some operation.
想来参观参观吗
Care for a little tour?
- 参观... - 对啊
- Of the...? - Yeah.
好啊 我很乐意
Yeah, I would.
那等你吃完 我再来找你吧
Well, then finish up, I'll come back for you.
好嘞 谢谢
Alrighty. Thanks.
您要点什么
May I take your order?
两杯软饮料和两份薯条
Two soft drinks and two fries.
您还要其它的吗 先生
Anything else for you, sir?
最重要的就是速度
Speed, that's the name of the game.
每一个麦当劳汉堡的第一站
The first stop for every McDonald's hamburger
是在烤架上 由两名厨师负责烤肉
is the grill. Manned by two cooks
他们唯一的工作
whose sole job
就是把那些鲜美的牛肉烤到完美
is to grill those all-beef beauties to perfection.
与此同时 肉饼被烘烤着
Meanwhile, as the patty cooks,
我们的备餐员会把小圆面包准备好
our dressers get the buns ready.
看好了 交换汉堡
Watch out. Burger crossing.
- 交换汉堡 - 交换汉堡
- Burger crossing! - Burger crossing!
每一个麦当劳汉堡里都有两种腌菜
Every McDonald's burger has two pickles.
一小撮洋葱和精确的两点番茄酱和芥末酱
A pinch of onions and a precise shot of ketchup and mustard.
- 那些工具是哪来的 - 我们自己做的
- Now where'd you get those? - We made them.
- 做的 - 对 定制的
- Made them! - Yeah, custom built.
整个厨房都是 下一站是完成制作的平台
The whole kitchen is. Next is the finishing station
在那里我们把一切都整合在一起
where we put the whole thing together.
然后
And...
瞧 一个新鲜美味的汉堡
Voila, a fresh delicious burger
从开始烤制到摆放上柜台
from grill to counter
只需三十秒
in 30 seconds.
你究竟是怎么想出这些来的
How the heck did you come up with this?
不是我想出来的 是我们一起
Oh I didn't. We did.
迪克·麦当劳 我弟弟
Dick McDonald, my brother.
嗨 我得告诉你 这真是最壮...
Hi. I gotta tell you, this is the most...
好吧 很高兴见到你
Well, it's nice to meet you.
- 薯条 - 薯条怎么了
- The fries. - What about them?
它们脆了五个百分点
They're five percent too crisp.
没有啊 很完美啊
No, they're perfect.
我们应该把油炸时间减少至两分五十秒
I think we should drop to two minutes, fifty seconds.
我们之前不就是这么长时间吗
Wasn't that what we were at before?
那就把油温从375度变成400度
400, not 375.
更高的油温 更少的时间
Higher temp, shorter cook.
- 我觉得炸得恰到好处 - 可以打扰一下吗
- I think they're spot on. - Excuse me, may I?
虽然和我无关 但我同意大个子的观点
None of my beeswax, but I'm with the big fella here.
我爱死薯条了 外面色泽金黄
I loved them. Golden brown on the outside.
里面松软雪白
Fluffy white inside.
不太油不太咸也不会太脆
And they're not too oily, salty, crunchy.
你谁啊
Who are you?
他是雷·克洛克
Oh, this is Ray Kroc.
和你通过话的那个卖多轴搅拌机的
The multi-mixer fella you spoke to.
你觉得我们什么时候能收到货
When do you figure we can expect them?
我们是空邮过来的 所以我说...
Umm, sent them blue-label air, so I'm...
- 那就好 - 等一下 等一下
- Good-good. - Hey, wait, wait.
等等
Wait.
等一下 我想请你吃晚餐
Wait a minute. I'm going to take you out to dinner.
可惜你真不是我的菜
You're really not my type.
请你和你哥哥
You and your brother.
为什么呢
What for?
在我这些年见过的食品服务行业中
This is the most remarkable restaurant I've seen in all my
你们家是最了不起的
years in the food service industry.
我可是全都见识过的
And I've seen it all.
我想听听你们的故事
I wanna hear your story.
我们当年还很年幼 饱受饥饿之苦
Well, we were young and hungry.
在整个新罕布什尔州都找不到工作
There wasn't a job to be had in all of New Hampshire.
所以我们决定收拾行囊去西部
So we decided to pack our bags and head west.
去好莱坞 我想进入电影行业
To Hollywood. I wanted to be in the movie business.
而迪克呢 他就是想要
And Dick, well, he wanted to be...
一份工作
Employed.
所以我们在哥伦比亚影业找到了开卡车的工作
So we landed jobs at Columbia Pictures driving trucks.
几年后 我们有了足够的积蓄
And after a few years, we had enough saved
去买一处属于我们自己的娱乐场所
to buy our own little piece of showbiz.
位于格伦多拉的一家美丽的小电影院
A beautiful little movie theater in Glendora.
免费观看大型开幕式
本应该是极成功的 但只可惜时机不对
Which would have been swell. Except for the timing.
免费观看大型开幕式
1929年10月24日美国爆发经济危机
那是1929年的9月
It was September of '29.
《百老汇掘金女郎》是一部1929年上映的彩色电影
前一分钟我们还在放映着《百老汇掘金女郎》
One minute we're screening the Gold Diggers of Broadway,
下一分钟就开始唱"兄弟 能施舍我一角钱吗"
and next it's, "Brother can you spare a dime?"
不能
I couldn't.
镇上没人能赚到钱
Nobody in town was making any money,
除了一个家伙 怀利·里德
except for one fella, Wylie Reid.
他有一家卖热狗和根汁汽水的小店
Had a hot dog and root beer stand.
无论怎样 人们还是要吃饭的吧
Hey, people still gotta eat, right?
所以我们决定开一家自己的小店
So we decide to open up our own little stand,
一家在阿卡迪亚卖热狗和橙汁的小店
hot dogs and orange juice, in Arcadia.
阿卡迪亚
生意也还算过得去 我们并没有大卖特卖
And it went okay. I mean we weren't going gang-busters.
阿卡迪亚
因为阿卡迪亚的人实在是太少了
There just weren't enough people in Arcadia.
与此同时 北面就是这个小镇 圣贝纳迪诺
Meanwhile, one town over is San Bernardino
我们想搬到这 但没有足够的资金买一家新店
and we want to relocate, but we got no money for a new stand.
圣贝纳迪诺
然后我弟弟有办法了
And that's when my brother here
他想出了一个棒极了的主意 告诉他吧 迪克
comes up with one of his brilliant ideas. Tell him, Dick.
就是...
Well...
他说 "我们为什么不直接把现有的店搬过去
He says, why don't we move the stand we've got.
运到卡车上拉过去" 太天才了 对吧
Put it on a truck. Genius, right.
只是还有一个小问题
Only there's one little problem.
连通两个小镇的路上有一座天桥
On the road between the two towns, there's an overpass.
欢迎来到圣贝纳迪诺
我们的店没办法通过
And the building won't clear.
欢迎来到圣贝纳迪诺
我当时就想 就这样吧 我们算了吧
Now I figure that's it, we're done for.
但是迪克却说 "为什么不把店锯成两半呢"
But then Dick says, "Why don't we saw the building in half?"
锯成两半
Saw it in half...
别卖关子啊
Come on.
于是我们把店搬了过去 又盖了起来
So we've moved the restaurant we're setting up shop.
但我们想做一点改进
But now we want to do a few tweaks,
因为是1940年嘛
because now it's 1940.
汽车餐馆正风靡一时
And drive-ins are all the rage.
简直是当时最火的了
I mean, they are the hottest thing going,
然后我就说 "迪克 我们得改成这样"
and I say, "Dick we gotta get in on this."
然后迪克说 "好"
And Dick says, "Okay".
两个月后 我们开张了
And two months later we open for business...
麦当劳著名的烤肉开卖了
McDonald's famous barbecue.
菜单上有二十七种食物
27 item menu.
穿着制服的女服务员直接把食物拿到车旁
Uniformed waitresses bring your food right to the car.
生意简直火爆极了 我们卖得都要上天了
And it goes gang-busters. We're going great guns.
但是接下来 生意开始下滑了
But then sales start to level off.
我们学来的汽车餐馆模式
The drive-in model as we learned,
- 有几个内在的问题 - 说来听听
- has a few built-in problems. - Tell me about it.
首先 是客源的问题
For starters, there's the customer issue.
可以说 汽车餐馆吸引来的
Drive-in's tend to attract, shall we say,
并不是很理想的客户
a less than desirable clientele.
- 青少年 - 都是开着改装老爷车的小流氓
- Teenagers. - Hot rodders and hooligans.
穿着牛仔裤的少年犯
Juvenile delinquents in blue jeans.
然后还有服务的问题
And then there's the service.
等待食物的时间无比漫长
It takes forever and a day for your food to arrive.
- 终于等到了... - 通常也都不对
- And when it finally does... - It's usually wrong.
是啊 侍者们都忙着躲避咸猪手以至于记不住
Yeah. The carhops are too busy dodging gropes to remember
你要的是草莓味汽水 而非樱桃味的
that you wanted strawberry phosphate, not cherry.
好歹她们还记得是汽水
Well, that's if they remember at all.
然后还有费用的问题 巨额的工资单
And then, there's the expenses. The huge payroll.
因为需要大量员工
Due to the large staff required.
碟子不断被打碎 要不就是被偷
Dishes constantly getting broken or stolen.
巨大的开销
Tremendous overhead.
所以一天 迪克突然意识到
So one day, Dick has a realization.
我们卖得最多的只有三种食物
He sees that the bulk of our sales are only in three items.
汉堡 薯条和软饮料
Hamburgers. French fries. Soft drinks.
共占百分之八十七
Eighty-seven percent.
所以我们对自己说 专注于真正卖价的商品吧
So we say to ourselves let's focus on what sells.
然后我们也正是那么做的
And that's exactly what we do.
牛胸肉不卖了 玉米粉蒸肉也不卖了
Brisket gone. Tamales gone.
但我们并没有止步于此
But we don't stop there.
我们把每一种都考虑了一遍
We look at everything.
还有哪些是我们不需要的
What else don't we need?
事实证明还有好多
Turns out quite a lot.
侍者们
Carhops.
走到窗边 自己拿食物
Walk up to a window, get the food yourself.
- 盘子 - 全都采用纸袋包装
- Dishes... - All paper packaging.
- 用完即丢 - 自动售烟机 自动点唱机
- Disposable. - Cigarette machines, jukeboxes.
把地痞流氓赶走
Drive out the riff-raff.
创造一个适宜家庭的舒适环境
Creating a family friendly environment here.
- 那也还不够 - 好吧
- But that's not enough. - Alright.
我们这一生都在借用其他人的想法
Our whole lives we'd piggybacked off other people's ideas.
我们需要的不仅仅是与众不同
We wanted something that wasn't just different.
我们要更优秀 要独一无二
It had to be better. It needed to be ours.
这让我们做了一个最重要的缩减
And that's what brings us to the biggest cut of all.
什么
Which was?
- 出餐时间 - 要在三十秒内出餐
- The wait. - Orders ready in 30 seconds.
- 而非三十分钟 - 令众人喜欢
- Not 30 minutes. - Mecca.
我们面面相觑了一晚上
We looked at each other one night.
我们想到一起了吧
You thinking what I'm thinking?
我们必须要拆除 重建
We're going to have to tear down, rebuild.
重新配置 重新思考整个项目
Reconfigure. Rethink the whole damn thing.
我们考虑将一个蒸蒸日上的店铺
We're talking about shutting down
关闭整改几个月
a thriving business for months.
大家会觉得我们疯了
People are going to think we're crazy.
我们当时的确疯了
We were crazy.
停业装修 开业在即 美国第一家 汽车汉堡餐厅 由麦当劳兄弟创建营运
你一定会为我们的做法拍手称赞
And you are going to love how we did it.
迪克 你来告诉他
Dick, you gotta tell him.
网球场吗
The tennis court?
他带我去了一个网球场
He brings me out to this tennis court.
精确地在地面上
And he's drawn this line,
画出我们厨房的格局
the exact dimensions of our kitchen.
水槽在右边 挤出器在左边
Sink on the right. Extruder on the left.
- 装袋和打包 - 打包
- Bagging and hood. - Hood.
- 配菜区 - 配菜区
- Garnish - Garnish.
- 这里是汉堡成品区 - 好了
- This is burger finish. - Got it.
这里放汉堡滑道
And this is burger slide.
这些都可以移走
We could just move those.
- 好了 - 多轴搅拌器 软饮料
- Okay. - Multi mixer, soft drinks.
我们把所有员工都叫了过去 模拟工作场景
We bring out our whole staff and we have them go through
让他们假装制作汉堡和薯条
the motions, making pretend burgers and fries.
好了 史蒂夫 你要预想到这点
Alright Steve, anticipate that.
把托盘平举
You gotta keep the tray level.
迪克就拿着棍子走来走去
And Dick is running around with this stick
标记各种设备的位置
marking where all the equipment should be.
食材塞好 托尼 等到实战的时候
Tuck in. Tony are you going to skip the pickles
你会不会忘记放腌黄瓜
when we're really doing it?
就这样翻来覆去 发现并解决问题
They do it over and over, hashing it out.
就像编排疯狂的汉堡芭蕾舞一样
Choreographing it like some crazy burger ballet.
那边什么情况
What's going on over there?
正确
Yes!
不对
No!
全部停手 停下来
Everybody stop! Stop!
一号配菜 二号配菜
Garnish one. Garnish two.
你们要放腌黄瓜和洋葱
You've got pickles, you've got onions.
你做的是汉堡
It's a goddamn hamburger.
- 好了 全部清场 - 大家清场
- Come on, clear off. - Let's clear off.
这次用粉色粉笔
It's time for the pink chalk.
这里放根汁汽水和橙汁
And then root beer, orange.
看到这边的开放空间了吗
See all this open space here now?
我们把炸薯条换了位置
We've rearranged the fry situation.
现在放在操作间左边 油炸机在操作间右边
So now it's stage left. The deep fryer stage right.
重新开始 很好
Begin! That's great.
- 大家加油 - 我们很赶时间
- Come on, guys. - We're pretty tied up here.
小心 主要是旋转台的时间控制
Watch out, it's the timing of the lazy-Susan.
这边是汉堡成品 你不能...
Those are finished burgers. You can't...
暂停
Hold it.
我还是坚信有更好的方案
I still think there's a third version.
- 你想移动哪台设备 - 所有的
- What do you want to move? - I want to move everything.
大家请回到操作间左边
Back to stage left, please.
都画出来了
We got it all drawn.
这样更好
This is better.
可以吗
Is that alright?
应该没问题
I think so.
我觉得... 我觉得... 继续模拟演习吧
I guess... I guess... let's assume our battle stations.
好的 开始
Okay. Okay.
终于 经过了六个小时的修改和演习
Finally, after about six hours of this,
我们大功告成
we get it just right.
这是一首关于效率的交响曲 并非浪费时间
It's a symphony of efficiency. Not a wasted motion.
做得正确 贾斯珀
Good form, Jasper.
腌黄瓜的动作很准
You feel good about those pickles!
番茄酱
Ketchup!
利用旋转台
Use your lazy-Susan.
再加把劲儿 赛斯
Put your back into it, Seth!
放腌黄瓜 腌黄瓜 加芥末酱
And pickle and pickle and mustard!
我们把设计图纸拿给了装修队
We take the layout to a builder,
完全按照我们的要求定制了厨房
custom build the kitchen to our exact specs.
高速系统就这样诞生了
Tada! The speedy system is born.
世界上第一条快餐生产线
The world's first-ever system to deliver food fast.
这是一场革命性的突破
It's totally revolutionary.
- 也完全是场灾难 - 为什么
- And a complete disaster. - Why?
开业当日 汽车都在停车位上等待
Opening day, cars pull up onto the lot
因为没有服务员接待
and they start honking immediately
他们都在按喇叭
because no carhop comes up.
请自己过来点菜
You place your order!
我们试图解释下车点单的经营模式
We try to explain to them the walk-up window.
他们一头雾水 不 他们大发雷霆
And they are bewildered. No they're furious.
让我下车是什么意思
What do you mean I gotta get out of my car?
大部分人就这样骂骂咧咧地开走了
Most of them just cuss us out and drive off.
少数留下的客人也是气急败坏
And the few that stay are mad as heck
因为他们要吃包在纸里的东西
because they're eating off paper
还要亲自扔垃圾
and they gotta discard their own trash.
- 为什么 - 你做得没错
- Why? - You're doing great.
对 我们不会下车
Yeah, we won't be coming out to the car,
但你们可以过来点单
but you can come on up.
欢迎光临麦当劳
Welcome to McDonald's!
我们可能低估了学习曲线
We may have underestimated the learning curve.
所以五点的时候 迪克已经开始计算
So by five o'clock Dick is calculating how much it's going
回归传统汽车餐馆模式的成本了
to cost to go back to drive-in.
但是我不想认输
But I am not ready to throw in the towel.
回忆起在好莱坞工作的日子
I go back to our old Hollywood days,
我对自己说 我们这次一定要做大
I think to myself, we gotta go big with this.
我们要举办演出
We gotta put on a show.
所以我说 "迪克 我要花重金重新开业
So I say, "Dick, I wanna throw a grand re-opening.
制片人 米高梅公司创建人
举办一场让路易·B·梅耶
A gala premiere that would
都自愧不如的豪华首映式"
put Louis B. Mayer to shame."
所以我们租了一些射灯
So we rent a bunch of spotlights.
和我们曾经在哥伦比亚片场用的那种一样
Same ones we used to haul around in the Columbia days.
我们准备了烟火 给小朋友变戏法的
We get sparklers, a juggler for the kiddies.
就是一场大型活动 大家成群结队
It is an event, people show up in droves.
- 之后... - 飞虫全来了
- And then... - The flies.
一定是被灯光吸引来的
They must've been drawn by all the lights.
成千上万 就像《埃及出记》的场景
Millions of them. It was like a scene outta Exodus.
法老见了也会放了以色列人
The Pharaoh would've released the Israelites.
彻底失败
Total disaster.
是时候放弃了
Now it is towel time.
第二天 迪克和我一起
The next day, dick and I meet up
讨论恢复传统经营模式
to discuss going back to the old format.
讨论期间 有人敲柜台窗户
And as we're talking there's a knock at the service window.
我告诉他我们关门了
I tell him we're closed.
- 我们关门了 - 但是他太可爱了
- We're closed. - But he looks so cute.
等下 等下 小朋友 你需要什么
Hang on. Hang on. What would you like, son?
我可以买包汉堡吗
Can I buy a bag of burgers from you?
- 三个吗 - 对 谢谢
- Three? - Yes, please.
我不好意思拒绝 重新开炉
And I feel bad, so I fire up the grill
给他做汉堡
and I make him a batch.
给你
There you are.
当他离开的时候 一辆车停了下来
As he's walking away from the service window a car pulls up.
然后又一辆
And then another.
迪克
Dick?
又一辆
And then another.
- 你好 欢迎光临麦当劳 - 你好
- Hello, welcome to McDonald's. - Hello there.
很快就在门口排起了长队
Pretty soon there's a line around the block.
- 消息不胫而走 - 生意走上了正轨
- The word has spread. - And it's off to the races.
我们打拼了三十年
And we are an overnight sensation
一夜之间引起了轰动
30 years in the making.
这就是我们的故事
So that's our story.
开加盟店
Franchise!
- 你说什么 - 开加盟店
- Beg your pardon? - Franchise!
开麦当劳的加盟店
Franchise the damn thing!
一家店太少了
It's too damn good for just one location.
应该到处都是麦当劳
There should be McDonald's everywhere.
越过海岸线 穿过大海
Coast to coast. Sea to shining sea.
- 克洛克先生 - 我...
- Mr. Kroc... - You know I...
我得向你们兄弟俩坦白
I got a confession I want to make to you boys.
我来加利福尼亚
I'm not out here in California
不是来参加商务会议的
for any kind of business meetings.
我为你们而来
I came out here for you.
几天前 我在密苏里的圣路易斯
A few days ago, I got into St. Louis, Missouri.
我当时在做生意 然后打开了地图
And I was doing some business, and I broke out my map.
手指向了一条向西的高速公路
And I followed my finger on one single highway west.
六十六号公路
Route 66.
- 克洛克先生 - 冥冥之中
- Mr. Kroc... - And something told me.
第六感告诉我应该开车上路
Something told me to get into my car and drive that highway.
知道我去了哪里吗 这里
And you know where it led me? Right here.
就是这里
Right smack damn here.
就是这家让人难以置信的店铺
Right to this unbelievable establishment.
当我看到你们的工作流程 营运模式
And when I saw these lines and your whole operation,
品尝了产品后 我明白这就是我们必须要做的
and tasted your product, I knew what needed to happen.
加盟 加盟
Franchise. Franchise!
加盟 加盟 加盟
Franchise! Franchise! Franchise!
我们已经尝试了
We already tried.
萨克拉门托 加州首府
五家 三家在南加州 一家在萨克拉门托
Five. Three in Southern California. One in Sacramento.
亚利桑那州首府
一家在菲尼克斯
And one in Phoenix.
就这么多 不再发展了
And that's all there will ever be.
- 为什么 - 两个词
- Why? - Two words.
质量控制
Quality control.
这么大的范围很难控制产品标准
It's almost impossible to enforce standards from afar.
那些地方一团糟 厨房脏乱差
Places were a mess, filthy kitchens,
菜单不统一
inconsistent menus.
萨克拉门托的门店之前还卖墨西哥卷
Sacramento was selling burritos.
看着自己珍贵的创造被如此糟蹋
To watch your precious creation be mismanaged like that.
- 还有你们的名字... - 麦克被气到住院
- Your name... - Put Mac in the hospital.
那...
Well...
你可以派人监督他们
So you put somebody in charge to supervise them.
- 找了 - 效果如何
- We did. - So what happened?
不尽人意
He obviously didn't do a great job.
那再招聘更优秀的人
So you hire somebody else, get somebody better.
我们的精力都很好地放在了
Our energies are better spent making this place
如何经营好这家店上
the best it can possibly be.
成功经营一家好餐厅
It's better to have one great restaurant
- 总比经营五十家普通餐厅强 - 没错
- than fifty mediocre ones. - Yeah, yeah, yeah.
但我还是认为 如果你们雇佣了对的人...
I still think if you hire the right guy...
雷 我们不感兴趣
Ray, we're not interested.
我觉得你们忽略了一些重点
I think you boys are missing something here that is...
我告诉你们 这些东西...
I tell ya, you got something here.
这是什么
What is that?
概念图
A concept.
这些是什么
What are those?
当顾客开车路过时可以注意到的
It's a way to make the place stand out
显眼设计
when you're driving by.
我称为"金色拱门"
The "Golden arches", I call them.
金色拱门
The golden arches.
谁想出来的
Who thought of that?
全部都是迪克的神奇点子
Oh, that's some pure Dick magic right there.
有没有运用到实体店
Did you ever build one like that?
只有一家
Just one.
菲尼克斯店
Phoenix.
菲尼克斯
亚利桑那州 17号公路
南出口 菲尼克斯
麦当劳
伊利诺伊州 阿灵顿海茨
艾瑟儿
Ethel!
在这里
In here.
天啊 我去了一家餐厅
Oh boy, I saw a restaurant,
我从来没有见过那样的餐厅
I've never seen a restaurant like this in my life.
他们拥有完全自动化系统
They've got this fully automated system.
称作高速系统
It's called the speedee system.
这个名字很适用 因为的确速度很快
Which is a good name for it, cause man it is speedy.
福特汽车公司建立者
感觉像亨利·福特那样的人
I'm telling you it's like something sprung from the mind
才能想出来的点子
of Henry Ford or something.
- 革命性创新吗 - 没错
- It's revolutionary? - It's revolutionary.
说得没错 革命性创新
Exactly what it is, it's revolutionary.
- 你想投资吗 - 我不知道 不确定
- And you want to invest in it? - I don't know. I don't know.
我不确定 不过我想参与其中
I'm not sure yet. But I just know I want to be part of it.
- 天啊 - 又来了
- Boy... - So here we go.
你什么意思
What do you mean by that?
一次性纸杯 折叠椅 多用途搅拌器
Wax cups, fold-a-nooks, multi-mixers.
现在又来了新想法
A new idea to chase.
那些东西帮我们买了现在的房子
Those things put a roof over our heads.
至少帮我买了这所房子
At least over mine.
"帮你"是什么意思
What do you mean over yours?
是帮"我们"
Over "our" heads.
这的确是个好房子 雷 房子很好
It's a good roof, Ray. It's a good house.
如果你不用每天忙东忙西的 也会是完美生活
It's a good life, if you weren't too busy to live it.
我们每年可以去会所两次以上
We could go to the club, more than twice a year.
天啊 一起出去散散步
Christ, just take a walk around the block together.
你现在不应该享受生活 别再瞎忙活了吗
Isn't it time to enjoy a little and stop chasing your tail?
什么时候你才能满足
When's enough going to be enough for you?
说实话吗
Honestly?
或许永远不会
Probably never.
大家都在努力 为什么我要止步不前
Why should I settle when other men won't?
我不知道 雷
I don't know, Ray.
我要是有一位有目光长远一些的妻子
Maybe if I had a wife with an ounce of vision.
给予我一些支持
Showed me an ounce of support.
对不起 我说错了
Sorry. Wrong word.
我一直在支持你
I've done nothing but support you!
对不起
Look, I'm sorry.
跑前跑后
Ups, down.
储蓄减少 你的计划方案
Dwindling savings, your schemes.
影剧院
■
码头风云
影剧院
约翰逊先生 关于先有鸡还是先有蛋的话题
Are you familiar with the concept of the chicken
你了解多少
and the egg, Mr. Johnson?
我认为用在这里 恰到好处
Because I think that's applicable here.
迪克
Hey, Dick.
这家伙究竟要干嘛
What is it with this guy?
- 为了国家 - 什么
- Do it for your country! - What?
如果你们不想为了自己发展加盟店
If you boys don't want to franchise for yourselves,
没关系 为了国家
that's fine. Do it for your country.
为了美国
Do it for America.
我开车经过了很多城镇
You know I've drove through a lot of towns.
许多小镇
A lot of small towns.
它们都有两个共同点
And they all had two things in common.
有法院和教堂
They had a courthouse and they had a church.
教堂顶部有十字架
On top of the church you got a cross,
法院顶部有国旗
and on top of the courthouse, they'd have a flag.
国旗 十字架
Flags crosses.
十字架 国旗
Crosses flags.
开车到处跑的时候 我一直在想
Driving around, I just cannot stop thinking about this
这家了不起的餐厅
tremendous restaurant.
我这话冒着亵渎神明的风险
Now at the risk of sounding blasphemous,
原谅我 金色拱门和那些建筑
forgive me, those arches have a lot in common
有很多共同点
with those buildings.
顶上有十字架的教堂
A building with a cross on top of it.
那是什么地方 是体面 有道德的人
What is that? It's a gathering place where decent wholesome
在国旗的保护下 聚在一起
people come together and they share values
和其他人分享价值观的地方
protected by that American flag.
同样地 两侧建有拱门的麦当劳
It could be said that beautiful building flanked by those arches
或多或少有着同样的价值和意义
signifies more or less the same thing.
店内不仅有美味的汉堡
It doesn't just say delicious hamburgers inside.
还代表着家庭 代表着社会群体
They signify family. It signifies community.
这是美国人聚在一起共同进餐的地方
It's a place where American's come together to break bread.
我正式告诉你们
I am telling you,
麦当劳可以成为新时代的美国教堂
McDonald's can be the new American church.
满足人类的肉体和灵魂
Feeding bodies and feeding souls
而且不仅在周天营业 兄弟们
and it ain't just open on Sunday boys.
是一周七天营业
It's open seven-days a week.
十字架
Crosses.
国旗
Flags.
拱门
Arches.
雷 让我们商量一下
Give us a minute, Ray.
当然
Sure.
我不知道
I don't know.
这是你的梦想 比你的梦想还要重要
This is your dream, it's bigger than your dream.
拱门 属于你的拱门 横跨美国
Arches. Your arches. Coast to coast.
我不能让你再重新经历失败
I can't put you through that again.
我知道你多么想实现梦想 你也应该去实现
I know how bad you want this. And you should have it.
你的糖尿病 上一次...
Your diabetes. Last time...
这次我们尝试不同的做法 从问题中汲取经验
We'll do things differently. Learn from our mistakes.
怎么做
How so?
严格管控一切 全面监督
Keep a tighter leash on everything. Complete oversight.
每一次修改都要经过我们同意
Every change goes through us.
你怎么知道他会听
Who says he's going to listen.
他必须听
We'll make him listen.
我们拟定合同
We'll draw up a contact.
白纸黑字 一目了然
Clear as day, black and white.
好
Fine.
- 兄弟们 开工吧 - 第一步怎么做
- Let's get to work, boys. - What's the first step?
一切交给我
Just leave that to me.
我们是一家充满活力的快速发展公司
We are a dynamic fast growing company.
准备进军国内的各大市场
And we're poised to make major inroads nationally.
除了能使我们在中西部站稳脚跟
So in addition to giving us a real strong foothold right here
德斯普兰斯这个地方还会带给其他加盟商
in the Midwest, the Des Plaines location would serve as kind of
强大的吸引力 如果你同意的话
a lure for other franchises if you will.
这些是什么
What are those?
- 什么 - 这些
- What are... - Those?
全新汉堡餐馆简介
我看看 这些啊
Let me see. Oh, those. Yeah.
这是我用来区分
That's just my little way of separating us
我们和其它餐馆的方式
from the rest of the pack.
你喜欢吗
You like 'em?
我把它们命名为金色拱门
I call them the golden arches.
你看着很眼熟 我们以前见过吗
You look familiar. Have we met before?
我觉得没有
I don't think so.
如果见过 我应该记得
I think I would have remembered that.
如果可以的话 请详细了解一下里面的内容
Peruse the inside here if you don't mind.
看看 读下这个
Take a look at the, read that.
折叠桌椅
The fold-a-nook.
像折叠床一样的东西 用在厨房里
It's like a Murphy bed, for your kitchen.
看看我们的蓝图
Take a look at the blueprints we got.
我们在当地建造了这个
We had those done locally.
我识人不忘
I never forget a face.
独特 新颖 全面创新
Unique. Original. Totally innovative.
它是独一无二的
There's nothing like this.
在整个餐饮服务业都找不出第二家
Nothing in the entire food service sector.
手册不错 做得很专业
Nice brochure, professionally done.
我们见过吗
Have we met?
你是那个卖纸杯的
The paper cup guy.
是 那是很久以前的事了
Yeah. That was a long time ago.
很久之前了
That was a long time ago.
你觉得怎么样
What do you think?
说不好
I don't know.
还有...
There's...
听着...
Look...
跟你说实话
I'm gonna level with ya.
我需要这笔钱
I need this one.
你觉得...
You think ahh...
你能帮上我什么忙吗
Is there anything you can do to help me out?
这样吧 我把你介绍给我同事
I'll tell you what, let me refer you to one of my colleagues.
他也许更能满足你的需要
Somebody who may be better suited to meet your needs.
谢谢
Thank you.
哈维·佩尔茨
住房抵押业务代理人
雷·克洛克
Ray Kroc.
地址...
Address...
杜松路143号
143 Juniper road,
伊利诺伊州 阿灵顿海茨
Arlington heights, Illinois.
家庭电话号码
Home telephone number?
用我办公室的电话吧
Ahh, use my office telephone number,
更方便联系到我
that's the best place to reach me.
好
Alright.
当然了 在我们批下资金之前
Of course we'll need an appraisal on your home
需要对你的房子进行估价
before we can issue funds.
出租
商业专用地
一定要成
Be right.
一次成功就好
Just be right one time.
就一次
One time.
朱恩 你和工程师安排好视察了吗
June, did you schedule the stakeout with the engineer?
- 都办妥了 - 那消防部门呢
- All set. - What about the fire department?
拿到汽车道设计的许可了吗
Did you get the approval for the driveway design?
昨天给他们留言了
Left a message with them yesterday.
挖掘许可证呢
Excavation permits?
我今天跟他们见面
I'm meeting with them today.
好
Alright.
对了 圣贝纳迪诺那边情况怎么样
Hey, what's going on with San Bernardino, by the way?
我刚跟迪克通过电话 他说他们正在处理
I just spoke to Dick, he says they're working on it.
他们正在处理
They're working on it?
他的原话
That's what he said.
雷·克洛克来电
Ray Kroc on the line.
- 嗨 雷 - 天啊 你们真是急死我了
- Hiya, Ray. - Boy, you boys are killing me.
为什么这么拖拉
What's the hold up?
我两个礼拜前就破土了
I break ground in two weeks.
这些事情需要时间
These things take time.
你的提议是彻头彻尾的改造
You're proposing substantial alterations.
我就只是加了个地下室和火炉而已
I'm adding a basement and a furnace, that's all.
我们需要建筑师详细审查
We need our architect to thoroughly review it
确保一切都安全无误 符合标准
and make sure everything is safe and up to code.
好吧 那他看了吗 去看了吗
Fine. Has he seen it yet, has he taken a look at it?
说实话 我不清楚
I'm not sure to be honest.
我的推土机二十三号要开工
I've got bulldozers rolling up on the 23rd.
这又不是我安排的 雷
I'm not the one who scheduled that, Ray.
- 你得缓缓了 - 缓缓
- I need you to take a breath. - Take a breath?
你知道如果延期的话 我要付出多大代价吗
Do you realize what it's going to cost me if I have to push?
希望不会到那一步
Hopefully, it won't come to that.
中西部的所有餐馆都有地下室和火炉
Every restaurant in the Midwest has a basement and a furnace.
- 这是标准配备 - 我明白
- This is standard stuff. - I understand.
但是餐馆上写的是我们的名字
But it's our name on that building.
不能因为我们没发现设计纰漏 结果地板塌陷
God forbid the floor caves in and people get hurt or worse
使人受伤或者发生更糟糕的事
because of some design flaw we missed.
我们把进度放慢点 确保一切都没问题
Let's just slow down a minute and make sure it's done right.
高速系统就到此为止了 是吧
So much for the speedee system, huh?
- 他刚挂你电话了吗 - 是的
- Did he just hang up on you? - Yes.
除非是突然断线了
Unless we got violently disconnected.
好吧
Okay.
没事的
It'll be fine.
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
■
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
操作台正面在哪里
Where's the... Where's the front of the apron?
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
即将开业
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
指给我看 好
Show me. Alright.
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
我很快速哦
麦当劳
有名的汉堡
一定要把窗户做得足够大
Just make sure the windows are big enough so the customers
这样顾客就可以看到餐厅 直接看见厨房
can look into the restaurant. All the way to the kitchen.
好像不太对 我看看
Doesn't look right. Let me see this.
- 雷 - 什么事
- Ray. - What?
圣贝纳迪诺来了封信
We got a letter from San Bernardino.
念给我听
Read it to me.
亲爱的雷 谢谢你写信分享你的想法
Dear Ray. Thank you for your letter sharing your idea
你想和可口可乐达成协议 让他们来赞助
to strike a deal with Coca-Cola to sponsor menu boards
德斯普兰斯新分店的菜单板
at the new Des Plaines location.
确实是个很有趣的想法
An intriguing notion, indeed.
你说得对 这样的安排
As you rightly point out, such an arrangement would provide
会给店里带来稳定的收入源
a steady source of revenue to the store
并且没有额外的劳工费
at no additional labor cost.
- 但是... - 但是 但是什么
- However... - However? However, what?
但是 这个设想不在我们的核心理念内
However, this is a concept that goes beyond our core beliefs.
麦当劳是以家庭为理念成立的
McDonald's was founded with the idea of families
而不是严格的商业经营
and not strict commerce.
混蛋 他们什么都不懂...
Sons of bitches, they don't know what the hell...
等等 诸如此类
And so on and so on...
拿着 先生们 接着工作吧
Here you go, gentlemen. Back to work.
我解释一下 它会做得很小
Let me explain. It'll be small,
放在底部 非常隐秘
along the bottom. Very discreet.
我们只是觉得把菜单变成广告这种想法
We're just not comfortable with the notion of turning our menu
让人很不适
into an advertisement.
这不是广告 是赞助
See it's not an ad, it's sponsorship.
- 但让人讨厌 - 这是白赚的
- It's distasteful. - It's free money!
有很多事情都来钱很快
There are plenty of things we could do to make a quick buck,
但并不意味着我们就该去做
that doesn't mean we should.
很多餐馆都这么做
Loads of restaurants do it!
- 我们不做 - 为什么不
- Well, we don't. - Why not?
因为我不想让自己
Cause I have no interest in indulging
唯利是图 不可自拔
in that sort of crass commercialism.
这不是麦当劳精神
It's not McDonald's.
20世纪50年代及60年代初摈弃传统生活与衣着的年轻人
没看出来我居然是在和披头族合作
I didn't realize I was partnering with a beatnik.
共和党被视为是社会保守主义
告诉你 我是正式的共和党员
I'll have you know I'm a card-carrying republican.
是是是 你也就骗骗我
Yeah, well you coulda fooled me.
他又挂了
He hung up again.
他只是... 他只是有点激动而已
He's just... he's just a little excitable, that's all.
这种性急的人 你不知道他有什么本事
A hot head like that, you don't know what he's capable of.
只是吓唬人罢了 迪克 他嘴坏心不坏
It's all bluster, Dick. His bark is worse than his bite.
英国首相 主张绥靖政策 从而加速了第二次世界大战
内维尔·张伯伦也是这么说的
That's what Neville Chamberlain said.
他会冷静下来的
He'll relax.
给他点时间
Give him some time.
伊利诺伊州 德斯普兰斯
你在干什么 拜托
What are you doing? Come on.
有空偷懒 就有空忙活 准备好
There's time to lean, there's time to clean. Let's go.
把帽子戴正
Put the hat on straight.
四百度 对吧
Four hundred degrees, right?
这就对了 就这么做
That'a boy, way to work.
很好
Nice.
这里只有一片腌菜
Hey, hey, hey. There's one pickle on there.
每片面包上要有两片腌菜 每一片都是
Two pickles on all the buns. Two pickles on all of them.
别... 别... 看好了 这样翻
Don't... don't... look, watch. Flip 'em like that.
你已经翻过一次了 也压过了
You already turned them over and press them one time.
这块太生了 好吧
And that one's too pink. Alright.
你...
And you...
把... 这些...
Get... these...
做得不错啊
That's pretty damn good.
- 你叫什么 - 弗雷德·特纳 先生
- What's your name? - Fred Turner, sir.
做得好 弗雷德·特纳
Nice work. Fred Turner.
弗雷德·特纳
Fred Turner.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我知道最近忽视你了
I know I've been neglecting you.
我们明晚去会所吃饭怎么样
What do you say tomorrow we go to supper at the club?
真的吗
Really?
真的
Really.
看看谁来了
Well, look what the cat dragged in.
大家好
Hello, everyone.
好啊 嗨... 你好吗
Hi there. Hi. Hey... How are ya?
- 晚上好 陌生人 - 很高兴见到你
- Evening, stranger. - Good to see you.
琳达·鲍伦刚刚去过 她很喜欢
Linda Ballen was just there, she adored it.
这次是在十四号球道的左边
This is on the left side of the 14th fairway.
用你的三号木[高尔夫球杆]
Use your three-wood.
- 嗯 三号木 - 利落击打
- Hmm, three-wood. - Hit it clean.
我听说阿卡普尔科[墨西哥南部港市]很神圣
I hear Acapulco is divine.
你喜欢哪里 艾瑟儿
Where do you like, Ethel?
西班牙
Umm, Spain.
西班牙 不错啊
Spain? Wonderful.
那里怎么样
Wow. How was it?
不 我是说 我在考虑那里
Oh no, I mean, I'm thinking about it.
你还没去过
Oh, you haven't been.
我们很想出去旅行一趟 对吧
Well, we're dreaming of a trip, right?
- 很好 - 嗯
- Great. - Yeah.
- 最近高尔夫打得怎么样 雷 - 最近吗
- How's your game, Ray? - Lately?
美国职业高尔夫运动员
- 完全没打 - 我也不是本·霍根
- Non-existent. - I'm no Ben Hogan myself.
当然了
No kidding.
嗯 不过我最近确实勉强打了一次
Haha, yeah. I did hit a hole-in-one of a sort,
一杆进洞
recently though.
我碰到了一个很吸引人的商机
I came across an interesting business opportunity.
非常有趣
Really interesting.
你们会想要分一杯羹的
You boys are gonna want a piece of this.
- 又来了 - 这次是什么 雷
- Here we go again. - What is it this time, Ray?
餐馆
Restaurant.
- 新型餐馆 - 怎么新了
- New kind of restaurant. - New how?
塞满奶昔和折叠桌椅的餐馆吗
Restaurant filled with milkshakes and fold-a-nooks?
折叠桌椅
Fold-a-nooks.
- 哈哈 - 我跟你开玩笑的 雷
- Ha-ha. - I'm just joking with you, Ray.
等等 杰克 你应该听他说完
Hold on, Jack. You should hear him out.
这次不同
This one's different.
多跟我们讲讲
Well, do tell us more.
我会的
I will.
这是件美事
This is a thing of beauty.
全自动化厨房
Fully automated kitchen.
我以前从来没有见过 是巨大变革
Likes of which I've never seen. It's revolutionary.
叫做高速系统
It's called the speedee system.
我喜欢的一点 是可以加盟
The thing I like about this, it's franchisable.
第一间店已经建起来在经营了
The first one is already up and running.
过来看看
Come on over and take a look.
可能会帮你们赚个几美金
Might make you boys a few dollars.
你什么都不用担心
You don't have to worry about a thing.
我们会负责之后的所有事情
We're in charge of everything after.
这些加盟店看起来完全一样
And all these franchises look exactly the same.
我以前从没觉得 现在发现年轻的员工更好
I would have never thought but younger workers are better.
他们拼命挣钱 充满野心
They're hustling, they're ambitious.
易如反掌
Easy as pie.
你只用付加盟费 我们来操心其余所有事
You just pay the franchise fee, we take care of everything else.
我会告诉你整个过程
I'll tell you the whole thing.
够近了 记下来 德鲁
Close enough, pick it up, Drew.
好了 开始吧
Alright, let's do this.
好了吗
Got her?
在那你会很高兴的
Okay. You'll be real happy there.
- 恭喜 - 好的
- Congratulations. - Alright.
上个月新增了三家加盟店
Three new franchises in the last month.
不错啊
Well, that's great.
怎么了
What?
不好说
I don't know.
怎么了
What?
难道你不觉得 从我们的经验来看
Don't you think maybe, given our experience,
这一切都发生得太快了吗
that this is all happening a little too quickly?
如果几间店一下同时运营
If they all pop up at once,
他怎么维持标准
how is he going to maintain standards?
伊利诺伊州 绍姆堡
■
新鲜乡村炸鸡
套餐赠送松饼
玉米棒子
炸鸡加松饼
■
混蛋
Son of a bitch.
使劲打 杰克
Give it a whack, Jack.
看看 这是什么
Hey! Look at this. What is this?
这是什么
Huh? What is that?
看着像个汉堡
It appears to be a hamburger.
不是麦当劳的汉堡 不是
Not a McDonald's burger it's not.
看看这番茄酱
Look at all that ketchup.
放了三片腌菜 而不是两片
You've got three pickles on there instead of two.
看看这 看看 生菜
Look at that. Look at that, lettuce.
没弄错吧 杰克 这是生菜
Really, Jack? Lettuce?
我们换个时间谈 好吗
Can we talk about this another time?
看看这肉饼 很悲剧地被烤老了
Look at the patty itself, that is tragically overcooked.
悲剧
Tragically!
我不知道 雷 我看着挺好的
I don't know, Ray, it looks good to me.
你知道什么是质量
What the hell do you know about quality?
我今天也去了你的加盟店
I was by your restaurant today too.
- 店有问题吗 - 有问题吗
- Yeah, what about it? - What about it?
你提供玉米棒子 你提供炸鸡
You got corn on the cob, you got fried chicken!
- 人们喜欢炸鸡 - 是吗
- People love fried chicken. - Do they?
那就让他们去吃炸鸡的地方吃
Let them go somewhere where they serve fried chicken.
还有你的厨房脏死了
And your kitchen is filthy!
你们到底什么毛病
What the hell is the matter with you guys?
我不知道你怎样 雷 但是我退休了
I don't know about you, Ray, but I'm retired.
你说这是个我们存钱的好地方
You said this would be a good place for us to park our money.
- 不 不 - 这是投资
- No, no. - It's an investment!
如果我想要工作 那我就去申请做厨师了
If I wanted a job, I would have applied for a cook position.
我的任何一间餐厅都不会要你做厨师
You couldn't get a job as a cook in one of my restaurants.
他什么毛病
What's his problem?
他就是个麻烦精
He's a pain in the ass is what he is.
彼此彼此 雷
Right back at ya, Ray.
- 艾瑟儿 - 在这里
- Ethel? - In here.
嗨
Hi.
雷 快点换衣服 晚餐七点开始
Ray, hurry and get changed. Dinner is called for seven.
我们今晚不去会所了
Yeah, we're not going to the club tonight.
你把我们的晚餐取消了
You canceled our dinner?
我退会了
I canceled our membership.
什么
What?
那些罗兰德·格林会所里的和我们不是一路人
Those Roland Green people, they're not really our kind.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
我已经不想跟那些懒散富人交往了
I've lost interest hobnobbing with the idle rich.
懒散富人
The idle rich?
你懂的 打打高尔夫 喝喝鸡尾酒
Yeah, you know playing golf, their Rob Roys.
他们沾沾自喜 自我满足
They're so complacent and content.
雷 你一定是在开玩笑吧
Ray. Please tell me you're joking.
这些都是我们的朋友
These are our friends.
不 我知道 我知道 知道吗
No, I know. I know. You know what?
我们可以交很多新朋友
You and I can make a lot of new friends.
没事的 我们会有新朋友
It's alright, we'll make new friends.
更适合我们的朋友
Friends that are more suitable, for us.
知道吗
You know?
你不这么觉得吗
Don't you think?
这样吧 给我点时间
You know what? Give me one second.
车库要把我逼疯了
The garage is driving me crazy.
我去清理打扫一下
Can I just go sweep it up and clean it up?
然后换身漂亮衣服
And then put a nice dress on,
我带你出去吃
I'll take you out for something to eat.
是 是
Yeah! Yeah!
太荒唐了
This is ridiculous!
还是走吧 你什么都得不到
Might as well go, you're not going to get anything!
- 做得好 大家 - 做得好
- Good job, guys! - Good job!
你看起来很忙
You look real busy!
跳舞跳舞 跳得不错啊 老兄
Fine, yeah dance, that's a good dance there, buddy.
做得好 除了做汉堡之外做什么都行
Good job, do anything but make a hamburger.
取消 取消我的订餐
Cancel! Cancel my order!
看看这漂亮的金边
Just take a gander at this handsome gold inlay.
你觉得这么华丽的手工
You're telling me such spectacular craftsmanship
不值8.95美金吗
isn't worth $8.95?
但我不感兴趣
But I'm not interested.
你对能成为家庭藏书骄傲的《圣经》
You're not interested in a Bible sure to be the pride of your
不感兴趣
family's home library?
你肯定知道 朱恩 嫉妒是七宗罪之一
As you no doubt know, June, envy is one of the seven deadly sins.
当你的朋友和邻居看到你书架上的
And that is what your friends and neighbors will be guilty of
这本皮边书时 就会对自己的嫉妒产生愧疚
when they see this leather-bound beauty on your bookshelf.
先生 这里是私人办公的地方
Sir, this is a private place of business.
我恐怕得请你离开了
I'm afraid I'm going to have to ask you to leave.
谢谢你抽出时间
Thank you for your time.
品食魁首销售公司 稍等
Prince Castle Sales. Oh, hold on.
雷 麦克打来的 你想接吗
Ray. It's Mac. Do you want to take this?
嗯 跟他说我晚点给他打过去
Ahh yeah, tell him I'll call him back.
等等
Hey, hey. Wait a minute.
你叫什么名字
What's your name?
莱纳德 莱纳德·罗森布拉特
Leonard. Leonard Rosenblatt.
你姓罗森布拉特 真的吗
Rosenblatt? Really?
一个犹太人为什么要卖天主教的《圣经》
What's a Jew doing selling Catholic Bibles?
维持生计
Making a living.
我对你有信心
I believe in you.
今日盛大开业
伊利诺伊州 沃基根
把腌黄瓜塞进去 这些可以转过去了 转稳了...
Tuck that pickle in. These are ready to spin. Smooth...
275度...
275...
前三十秒不要加盐 好吗 都不错 伙计们
No salt for 30 seconds, okay? Looking good, fellas!
一切都不错 露出你的笑容
Looking good! Big smiles!
要是有时间偷懒 你就有时间干活
If you've got time to lean, you've got time to clean!
通常给十岁以下的 不过为你破个例
It's normally ten and under, but for you I'll make an exception.
我喜欢 太棒了
Love it. Nice.
我的新加盟商太棒了
My new franchisees are great.
男的在后厨亲力亲为
He's in the back working in the kitchen.
女的在店前给孩子发棒棒糖
She's out front, handing suckers out to the little kids.
夫妇搭配 干活不累
Husband and wife, side by side.
完美组合
Like a real team.
这真让人喜闻乐见
It was really something to see.
棒极了 你不觉得吗 艾瑟儿
Wonderful, don't you think, Ethel?
- 我想是吧 对 - 没错
- I suppose it is, yeah. - Yeah.
像队友一样
Like teammates.
周五晚餐我做了安排
I made supper plans for us, Friday.
我猜你不是要重返罗兰德·格林会所吧
I'm guessing you didn't rejoin Roland Green?
不是... 不是 一个更好的地方
Well no... no. Someplace far better.
号码是B-5
B-5!
太咸了
So salty.
我口重
I love the salt.
你是做什么的 阿特
So what do you do, Art?
退伍后不久我就做了个维修下水管道的
Had a little plumbing business going for a while after getting
小生意
out of the service.
目前我也卖吸尘器 同时还教一些钢琴课
Now I sell vacuum cleaners and give piano lessons on the side.
大忙人 真有你的
Busy guy. Good for you.
吸尘器 水管维修 钢琴课
Vacuums, plumping, piano lessons.
你真是个全才
You're a Jack of all trades.
是啊 只要能养家糊口什么都得做 对吧
Yeah, whatever puts food on the table, right?
你一定很骄傲吧
You must be so proud?
如果我让你不仅仅可以"养家糊口"
How would you like to do more than
你意下如何
"put a little food on the table"?
中奖了
Bingo!
她好兴奋
She's excited.
你有什么办法
What'd you have in mind?
我会告诉你们六个字
I'm going to give you three words.
我希望你们牢记这六个字
I want you to take those three words home with you tonight.
麦当劳是我家
McDonald's is family.
这是不是很暖心
Isn't that great?
你们知道我看见那个的时候会说什么吗
You know what I say when I see that?
家庭 我们是一个大家庭
Family. We're one big family.
对不对
Aren't we?
有人等着吃我们做好的食物
We've got mouths to feed.
这就是家庭
That's a family.
我在寻找一些优秀的男人
I'm looking for a few good men.
和女人 不怕脏活累活
And women! Who aren't afraid of hard work.
不怕卷起袖子亲力亲为的人
Aren't afraid to roll up their sleeves.
老生常谈了
Cliche, I know,
但我要的是有干劲 想尽办法赚钱的人
but I'm looking for scrappers, hustlers.
愿意冲在前面干活的人
Guys who are willing to roll up their sleeves.
有野心的人
People with drive.
有雄心壮志
They got a little fire in the belly.
还要有一些胆识
Got a little chutzpah!
今天我站在你们面前 将为你们提供
I stand right here before you today and I'm going to offer you
某种如金子般珍贵的东西
something as precious as gold.
知道是什么吗 谁知道
You know what that is? Anybody?
谁知道 机遇
Anybody? Opportunity!
是机遇 机遇
It's opportunity! Opportunity.
进步的机遇
Opportunity to advance.
前进的 上升的 进步的机遇
To move forward. To move up, to advance.
成功的机遇
To succeed.
走向胜利 迈向未来 你有无限可能
To win. To step up. The sky's the limit.
你的人生不设限 机不可失
The sky's the limit. Grab the brass ring!
给自己一次实现美国梦的机会
Give yourself a shot at the American dream!
拥抱美国梦吧
Put your arms around the American dream!
机遇... 因为我想告诉你们 在麦当劳...
Opportunity... 'Cause I'll tell you something, at McDonald's...
犹如我们伟大的祖国一样
Just like this great nation of ours,
在那些重体力活中...
some of that elbow grease...
我保证 如果你有胆量
I guarantee if you've got the guts,
有头脑 有梦想
got the gumption, you've got the desire.
我向你保证 你能够成功
I guarantee ya, you can succeed.
在那些金色拱门背后藏着金子等你挖掘
There's gold to be had at the end of those golden arches.
金色拱门 金色拱门
Golden arches. Golden arches.
谁愿意跟我干 愿意跳上这个通向成功的阶梯
Now who's with me? Who wants to jump on that ladder to success?
成为麦当劳大家庭的一分子
Become part of the McDonald's Mishpuchah.
谁想加入
Now who's with me?
来吧 让我看到你们的手
Come on, let me see some hands!
- 我要加入 - 还有这里
- I'll join! - Here!
这才像样 还有谁
There you go. Who else?
俄亥俄州 达顿
威斯康辛州 麦迪逊
威斯康辛州 密尔沃基
密歇根州 大急流城
威斯康辛州 基诺沙
伊利诺伊州 迪凯特
麦当劳
McDonald's!
不错 阿特 做得不错
Good, Art, good job!
谢谢 先生
Thank you, sir.
这家伙胆子真是大
The nerve of this guy!
怎么了
What?
你猜他管德斯普兰斯店叫什么
Guess what he's calling his Des Plaines store.
麦当劳一号店
McDonald's number one.
那... 我们是什么
Then... what are we, then?
他还能再得意忘形些吗
Could his head get any bigger?
女士们先生们 本架飞机即将开始初始下降
Ladies and gentlemen, we are about to begin our initial descent
降落机场为明尼阿波利斯-圣保罗机场
into Minneapolis-St. Paul.
克洛克先生 欢迎来到明尼阿波利斯
Mr. Kroc, welcome to Minneapolis,
很荣幸见到你 大声喊出M
wonderful to see ya! Gimme an M!
M
M!
大声喊出C
Give me a C!
C
C!
大声喊出D
Gimme a D!
D
D!
麦当劳
McDonald's!
雷 怎么样
Ray, how is it?
在芝加哥你也找不出比这好吃的
You can't even top that in Chicago.
没错 我们这里可不是闹着玩的
Well, we don't mess around up here.
好家伙 我要向主厨致敬 这太美味了
Boy, my compliments to the chef. That's wonderful.
我可以给你找来比主厨更厉害的
I can do you one better.
- 餐厅老板怎么样 - 好啊 何乐而不为
- How about the owner? - Sure, why the hell not.
罗利
Rollie?
Rollie.
吉米 很高兴见到你
Jimmy, great to see ya.
- 罗利 近来如何 - 不错
- Rollie, how are ya. - Oh, wonderful.
罗利·史密斯 雷·克洛克
Rollie Smith, Ray Kroc.
十分荣幸
Real pleasure.
老天 我不得不说 你的餐厅真心不错
Boy, I tell ya, you got one hell of a restaurant here.
这话出自你口 我真是受宠若惊
Well, coming from you that's quite a compliment.
我名声远扬了
My reputation precedes me.
- 我很崇拜你 - 那... 一块儿坐吧
- I'm a great admirer. - Well umm... sit down.
- 我不想妨碍你们 - 请坐
- I don't want to interrupt. - Have a seat.
那我就坐一会
Well, maybe just a minute.
这是弗雷德·特纳 我的合伙人
This is Fred Turner my associate.
欢迎
Welcome.
- 牛排煎得还可以吗 - 棒极了 完美
- Steaks cooked okay? - Excellent. Perfect.
我们的目标是...
Our intention is to ahh...
扩展到中西部以外的众多地区
Expand pretty far beyond the Midwest.
我们不打算止步于此 我们不打算...
We're not going to settle here. We're not gonna...
我们计划扩张到中西部以外的多数地区
We're going to expand far beyond the Midwest.
你显然在明尼阿波利斯已经站稳脚跟了
You've clearly got a warm and loving home here in Minneapolis.
是的 貌似是这样
Yeah, so it seems.
没错 这个镇子的人就是吃不够麦当劳
Yeah, this town just can't get enough of McDonald's.
给您 先生
Here you go, sir.
再给我朋友来一杯加拿大会所[威士忌]
Another Canadian club for my friend.
好的 先生 马上来
Yes, sir. Coming right up.
谢谢
Thank you.
实际上 我看这里还有足够的市场
In fact, I'd say there's sufficient enthusiasm
开分店
to support another.
在另外一个地段
A second location?
一想到这个
You know, come to think of it,
我认识一个加盟经营分店的完美人选
I know the perfect person to own and operate.
真的吗
You don't say?
一个知道如何建立起一家优秀餐厅的人选
Somebody who knows what it takes to build a great restaurant.
一个有二十多年涉足餐饮行业
Someone with more than 20 years experience
经验的人选
in the food service industry.
是谁
Who?
- 我 - 你
- Me. - You!
还真是意料之外
Oh! That's a shock.
他真幽默
He's funny.
我有专业知识 我有充足的资金
I've got the know-how, I've got the backers
我还知道一个完美的地段
and I've got the perfect location.
你知道亨内平大道吗
Are you familiar with Hennepin Avenue?
双子城指明尼阿波利斯和圣保罗这两个城市
那是整个双子城地区最为繁华的
That's one of the busiest commercial arteries
商业主干道之一
in the whole twin-cities.
那有一个黄金位置的店铺最近正在招商
There's a prime site that's recently become available.
亨内平大道转角的一英亩的店铺 而且...
Full acre on the corner of Hennepin and...
- 克洛克先生 - 什么
- Mr. Kroc? - Yeah?
你想认识她吗
Would you like to meet her?
好 当然
Yeah. Sure.
雷 你会在双子城
So Ray, how long are you here with us for,
- 待多久 - 什么
- in the twin-cities. - Huh?
你会在这里待多久
How long are you in town?
我... 还不确定
I... not sure yet.
如果二位能够拨出些时间
If you gentlemen could steal a second,
我十分愿意亲自带二位到罗利说的那个
I would love to personally give you a tour of this site on
在亨内平大道上的店铺去看看
Hennepin that Rollie is talking about.
他很会选址
He knows how to pick 'em.
我是说这个地方的面积足够开一家饭馆
I mean this place has enough room for the restaurant,
还有停车场 甚至是孩子们玩耍的游乐场
the parking, possibly a playground for the little ones.
雷·克洛克 认识下琼·史密斯
Ray Kroc meet Joan Smith.
我太太
My wife.
- 很荣幸认识你 - 很高兴见到你
- Pleasure to meet you. - Pleasure to meet you.
一块坐 跟我们喝一杯吧
Well, join us. Have a drink with us.
十分乐意
I'd love that.
- 各位怎么样 - 不错
- How are you guys? - Good.
这是弗雷德·特纳 他是...
This is Fred Turner, he’s a…
我们在麦迪逊 密尔沃基
We did Madison, Milwaukee,
基诺沙 大急流城开了店
Kenosha, Grand Rapids.
在芝加哥地区有三家
Ahh, we've got the three in the Chicago area.
吉姆负责明尼阿波利斯的店
Oh, Jim's here in Minneapolis.
是圣保罗
St. Paul.
在俄亥俄州的达顿也有一家
Got one in Dayton, Ohio.
没错
That's right.
你绝对晕头转向了吧 克洛克先生
You must be positively dizzy, Mr. Kroc.
拜托 叫我雷
Please, call me Ray.
雷...
Ray...
增长得很快
That's some growth.
是的 我们发展得不错 是吧 弗雷德
Yeah. We're doing good, right Fred?
是的 先生
Yes, sir.
对 我们做得很好
Yeah, we're doing good.
你什么时候开始创业的
When did you start it?
你说什么
Hmm? Sorry?
你哪一年创立麦当劳的
What year did you start McDonald's?
哪年
The year?
我是在1954年创立的
I started it in 1954.
成绩非凡啊
Remarkable.
是的
Yeah.
- 我该回去了 - 回哪
- Well, I should get back. - Back?
- 回去弹琴 - 当然
- To my piano. - Oh, of course.
你最喜欢的歌是什么
What's your favorite song?
多年的最爱
All-time favorite.
- 《天堂的便士》 - 《天堂的便士》
- Pennies from heaven. - Pennies from heaven.
- 是个好女人 - 我知道
- Great gal. - I know.
我还卖过一段时间的钢琴
I sold pianos for a while.
♪ 每次下雨 ♪
Every time it rains it rains
♪ 都是天堂的便士落入世间 ♪
Pennies from heaven
♪ 你难道不知道每朵云中都藏着 ♪
Don't you know each cloud contains
♪ 天堂的便士 ♪
Pennies from heaven
♪ 你会看见你的财富 ♪
You'll find yor fortune falling
♪ 降落在整个小镇 ♪
All over town
唱得不错
Sounds pretty good.
♪ 确保你的雨伞 ♪
Be sure that your umbrella
♪ 大头朝下 ♪
is upside down
♪ 用它们换一袋 ♪
Trade them for a package
♪ 阳光和鲜花 ♪
of sunshine and flowers
♪ 假如你想得到所爱之物 ♪
If you want the things you love
♪ 你一定要淋雨 ♪
You must have showers
♪ 所以当你听到雷声 ♪
So when you hear it thunder
♪ 别到树下避雨 ♪
Don't run under a tree
♪ 会有便士从天而降 ♪
There'll be pennies from heaven
♪ 落在你我身上 ♪
for you and me
没忍住
Sorry.
是的 是的
Oh yes, yes.
你们会在此之外继续扩张 还是这个...
Will you be expanding beyond this or is this...?
毋庸置疑 我们会开遍各地
Oh, no doubt. We'll be everywhere.
太激动人心了
Very exciting.
除了汉堡以外还供应什么
What is on the menu beyond hamburgers?
我们还供应薯条 奶昔和软饮
Well, we've got French fries, milkshakes and soft drinks.
- 雷 - 在楼下
- Ray? - Down here!
我想我有合适的人选给你推荐
I think I've got some people for you.
我认识了一对年轻夫妇 很有担当
I met this young couple. Very committed.
来自格伦维尤
They're from Glenview.
高中恋情修成正果 结婚五年了
High school sweethearts, married for five years and
他们正在寻找共同经营的生意机会
they're looking for a business they can operate together.
他们对加盟也兴奋不已
And they seem very excited.
别管他们了 今时不同往日了
Yeah, forget that. Everything's changed.
- 你要喝一杯吗 - 不要... 怎么不同了
- You want a drink? - No... changed, how?
不要再想芝加哥郊区了 眼光放长远些
Forget the Chicago suburbs. Think bigger.
- 长远些 - 我不必再找他们加盟了
- Bigger? - I'm not chasing them anymore.
他们现在来求着我了
They're chasing me now.
- 什么... - 出差 这次的出差
- What is...? - The trip! The trip I just took.
- 出差 怎么样 - 凯旋而归
- The trip. How was it? - Triumphant.
他们铺出了红地毯
They rolled out the red carpet.
他们亲吻这枚戒指
They're kissing this ring.
他们现在求着我要加盟麦当劳
They're begging me for McDonald's now.
给 喝一杯
Here, have a drink.
- 那真不错 - 是啊 绝对的
- That's nice. - Yeah, sure is.
我相信
I'm sure.
那么就 大声高呼雷蒙德主教第一
Well, then all hail pope Raymond the first.
说得对
Damn right.
说得太对了
God damn right.
- 雷 - 怎么了
- Ray? - Yeah?
- 我们有个小麻烦 - 等一下
- We have a small problem. - Wait a minute.
我们怎么会资金不足呢
How can we be almost out of capital?
你的收入 也就是每个月店铺收益的提成
Well, your revenue, the monthly cut of the stores.
是净收入的1.4%
1.4% of net.
- 1.4吗 - 对
- 1.4? - Yeah.
1.9减去迪克和麦克的0.5
1.9 minus Dick and Mac's half-percent.
克洛克先生将获得加盟店赚取净利润的1.9% 其中0.5%需支付给理查德·麦当劳和莫里斯·麦当劳
麦当劳先生 雷·克洛克打来电话
Mr. McDonald, Ray Kroc's on the line.
克洛克先生将获得加盟店赚取净利润的1.9% 其中0.5%需支付给理查德·麦当劳和莫里斯·麦当劳
很高兴见到你
Good to see you.
- 你好 雷 - 我想重新谈判
- Hi, Ray. - I want to renegotiate.
重新谈判什么
Renegotiate what?
我的条款 我的破条款
My deal. My lousy deal.
1.4连我每月的固定花销都不够
1.4 doesn't even cover my monthly nut,
更不用说扩展业务了
let alone drive expansion.
雷 那些是固定条款
Ray, those are the terms.
- 不够好 - 那几乎是我们分得的三倍了
- It's not good enough. - It's almost triple our cut.
那你们也应该拿更多 对不对
You should be getting more too then, shouldn't you?
我们不贪心
We are not greedy men.
这和贪心无关
Greed has nothing to do with it.
如果我有更多资金周转
If I had more money to work with,
店铺加盟的速度会是现在的两倍
I could be growing this thing at twice the pace.
我们对目前的扩张速度并无不满
We have no beef with the current rate of expansion.
我什么都没做成 在宾夕法尼亚都没有店
I've got nothing, not one location in Pennsylvania.
- 在纽约也没有 - 将来会有的
- Nothing in New York. - All in good time.
- 德州也是空白 - 我坚信那天会到来的
- Nothing in Texas. - I have no doubt it will come.
我在外边为你们兄弟俩累死累活
I'm out here breaking my neck for you guys.
你做得十分出色
And you're doing a bang-up job.
那我就应该不仅仅保持个
Well, then I should be doing a heck of a lot better than just
- 不赚不赔 - 我不知道说什么了
- breaking even. - I don't know what to say.
- 说你会重新谈判 - 我不能
- Say you'll renegotiate. - I can't.
不能还是不想
Can't or won't?
提高你的分红对加盟商不公平
Upping your cut would be unfair to the franchisees.
加盟商们的情况好着呢
The franchisees are doing just fine!
我是那个快撑不下去的
I'm the one that's drowning here.
当初你是自由自愿签订协议的 雷
You freely and willingly agreed to the terms of your deal, Ray.
没人拿枪逼着你
Nobody put a gun to your head.
- 百分之四 - 不行
- Four percent? - No.
- 百分之三点五 - 雷...
- Three and a half percent? - Ray...
- 行不行 - 不行
- What? - No!
该死的
Goddamn it!
迪克
Dick.
他是一个麻烦鬼吗 是的
Is he a pain in the rear? Yes.
他有些不受控制吗 没错
Does he have a few screws loose? You bet.
但这不代表他会做出损害我们的事情
But that doesn't mean he's going to do us any harm.
你还要继续这样多久 麦克
How long are you going to keep this up, Mac?
继续什么
Keep up what?
那副假装天下太平的样子
The whole "Everything is fine" act.
鸡圈里进了一条狼
There's a wolf in the henhouse.
我们放他进去的
We let him in!
我就不该听你的
I never should have listened.
我们的合同就是为了防止这样的事情 迪克
We have a contract for just this sort of thing, Dick!
我应该相信我的直觉的
I should have trusted my gut.
所以这是我的错吗
So it's my fault, huh?
就像那个电影院一样
Just like the movie theater?
真抱歉我想让你实现梦想
Well, I'm sorry I wanted you to have your dream.
九十四美元
Ninety-four dollars.
芝加哥燃气电力公司
最后通知
这些破东西的开销高得离谱
It's unbelievable what these suckers cost to run.
我老爸以前开了一家冰淇淋店
My pop used to own an ice cream parlor.
他因制冷成本过高破产了
He went belly-up from the refrigeration costs.
真的吗
Really?
今天有个人来电话了
A man called today.
伊利诺伊第一联邦银行
Illinois First Federal.
他说什么事了吗
Did he say what he wanted?
不如你来告诉我
Why don't you tell me?
他有什么事
What did he want?
雷
Ray...
怎么了
What?
你抵押了我们的房子
Did you mortgage our home?
我们有可能会一无所有的
We could lose everything.
我明确说过 有事请打我办公室电话
I specifically said the office is the best place to reach me!
克洛克先生 我们打过好多次
I tried there, Mr. Kroc. Numerous times.
你们没有权利打我家里的电话
You have no right to call me at my home.
这是公然侵犯我的隐私
It is a blatant invasion of my privacy!
恕我直言 先生 你已经有三个月不还贷款了
With all due respect, sir, when you're three months behind on
你现在无权要求我们
your payments you don't get to pick and choose
怎么联系你
where we contact you.
雷
Ray?
突击检查
Surprise inspection.
你在这里干什么
What are you doing here?
我碰巧路过 就顺便过来看看
I just came up to see how things are going?
一万两千四百美元
$12,400.
一个月做到这些很不错了
That's pretty good haul for month one.
能赚更多的
Could be bigger.
我不喜欢在娱乐时谈工作
I hate to mix business with pleasure.
我也是
I don't.
不过我的开销
But my expenses.
怎么了
What about them?
要比预期的高一点
Well, they're a bit higher than anticipated.
尤其有一点 那个该死的大储存间
One thing in particular, that dang walk-in.
那笔钱就是骗人的把戏
That bill is a real whopper.
但那些冰淇淋存放是个问题
It's a problem, all that ice cream.
我可不希望这成为一个阻碍
I don't want to overstep my bounds here.
不过 我们可能找到解决方案了
But, we may have found a solution.
或者说 实际上是琼找到的
Or Joan did, actually.
不是吧
You don't say?
如果我告诉你我有办法让各位店主
What if I told you there was a way all of your owner-operators
每年省下几百美金的电费
can save literally hundreds of dollars a year
会怎么样
in electrical costs?
同时也能使做奶昔的时间
And reduce the time that it takes to make a milkshake,
减少一半
by half.
我猜不出
I'll bite.
■
餐饮业月刊
速溶粉
是奶昔粉
It's a powdered milkshake.
速溶粉
价格是冰激凌的零头
Costs a fraction of ice cream
而且也不需要冷藏
and there's no refrigeration necessary.
它包含了奶粉
It contains powdered milk.
增稠剂和乳化剂
Thickening agents and emulsifiers
可以营造出冰激凌的口感
simulate the texture of ice cream.
尝起来跟真的一样
Tastes just like the real thing.
像做馅饼一样简单
It's easy as pie to make.
在一杯水里放一包 然后搅拌
You put a packet into a glass of water and stir it.
我明白 这对你们做过乳制品的人来说
I know maybe a tad blasphemous,
算是有点亵渎神明
what with your dairy background and all.
私心来说 我觉得这是个不错的主意
Personally, I think it's a marvelous idea.
要巧克力味还是香草味
Chocolate or vanilla?
香草味
Vanilla.
好物只留给愿意等待的人
Good things come to those who wait.
你觉得如何
What do you think?
我应该正在喝一杯美味的香草奶昔
I think I'm drinking a delicious vanilla milkshake.
我能尝尝吗
May I?
美味无法抵抗
I can't resist.
你怎么看
So what do you say?
先在我们店试营一下 如果效果好的话...
We try it out at our place and then if it goes well...
你就全国推广
You roll it out nationally.
可以 让我好好想想
I could. Yeah. Let me think about it.
你说了算
You're the boss.
麦当劳
McDonald's.
我找到了可以帮你我
I just found a way to save you, me,
和所有的店主省下每年几百元电费的
and all the owner-operators literally hundreds of dollars
方法
a year in electrical costs.
- 是什么呢 - 三个字 奶昔粉
- And what would that be? - Two words, powdered milkshake.
告诉你 我发现了
I'm telling you I came across
一个很了不起的产品 叫速溶粉
a remarkable product called inst-a-mix.
如我所说 这是种奶昔粉
Like I said, it's a powdered milkshake.
价格是冰激凌的零头
It's a fraction of the cost of ice cream
而且也不需要冷藏
and requires no refrigeration.
雷...
Ray...
我亲自实验了 尝起来跟真的一样
I tell ya, I tried it myself, it tastes just like the real thing.
味道不错 有巧克力味 香草味
It's delicious. Comes in chocolate, comes in vanilla.
我喜欢香草味
Me, I'm a vanilla man.
雷 我们对不含牛奶的奶昔不感兴趣
Ray, we have no interest in a milkshake that contains no milk.
既然你说起了 我们不如在汉堡里面加木屑吧
Why don't we add sawdust to the hamburgers while we're at it?
薯条用冷冻的
Frozen French fries!
你不想省一笔吗
You don't want to save a bundle?
不能这么省
Not like that.
我们在讨论的是同样的美味口感
We're talking about the same great taste.
降低成本 但还能保持同样的口感
Same great taste while boosting the bottom line.
这是奶昔 雷
It's called a milkshake, Ray!
真正的牛奶 永远都是
Real milk, now and forever!
我明白
I understand.
最后通知
伊利诺伊第一联邦银行
■
最后通知
伊利诺伊第一联邦银行
我只是想让你延长一下期限
I'm just asking you to extend my line.
最后通知
伊利诺伊第一联邦银行
除非你家的估值增加或者你偿清贷款
Until you build more equity in your home or pay down the loan,
最后通知
伊利诺伊第一联邦银行
否则我无能为力
there's nothing I can do.
我的生意做得很好
My business is booming.
可惜这都是无形资产
Unfortunately, that's immaterial.
我在九个州有十三家店面
Well, I've got thirteen locations in nine states.
- 这是房产抵押贷款 - 那给我商业贷款
- It's a home-equity loan. - Then give me a business loan.
这十三家店 归你所有吗
These thirteen locations, you own them?
- 是我个人吗 - 那是你的生意 对吗
- Me personally? - It's your business, correct?
- 你有所有权吗 - 我是加盟商负责人
- You own it? - I'm the head of franchising.
是我让它发展起来的
I'm the one behind this growth.
这一切都很好 不过你得有资产
Well, that's all well and good, but you need assets.
你去过麦当劳吗
Have you been to a McDonald's?
因为我们最近在芝加哥内陆开了三家
Because we've got three right here in the Chicago land area.
你应该顺路去看一下
You should come by and take a look.
不 我很乐意带你参观 让你更好地体会一下
No, I would love to give you a tour to give you a better sense
- 我说的话 - 谢谢
- of what I'm talking about. - Thank you.
克洛克先生
Mr. Kroc?
有什么可以效劳的
Can I help you?
没有 不过或许我可以为你效劳
No, but perhaps I can help you.
哈利·索恩本 很高兴见到你
Harry Sonneborn, nice to meet you.
哈利·J·索恩本
财务副总裁
美味冰公司
哈利·J·索恩本
财务副总裁
美味冰公司
哈利·J·索恩本
财务副总裁
美味冰公司
哈利·J·索恩本
财务副总裁
美味冰公司
哈利·J·索恩本
财务副总裁
美味冰公司
哈利·J·索恩本
财务副总裁
美味冰公司
哈利·J·索恩本
财务副总裁
美味冰公司
哈利·J·索恩本
财务副总裁
美味冰公司
哈利·J·索恩本
财务副总裁
美味冰公司
哈利·J·索恩本
财务副总裁
美味冰公司
哈利·J·索恩本
财务副总裁
美味冰公司
哈利·J·索恩本
财务副总裁
美味冰公司
哈利·J·索恩本
财务副总裁
美味冰公司
哈利·J·索恩本
财务副总裁
美味冰公司
哈利·J·索恩本
财务副总裁
美味冰公司
哈利·J·索恩本
财务副总裁
美味冰公司
哈利·J·索恩本
财务副总裁
美味冰公司
哈利·J·索恩本
财务副总裁
美味冰公司
哈利·J·索恩本
财务副总裁
美味冰公司
哈利·J·索恩本
财务副总裁
美味冰公司
哈利·J·索恩本
财务副总裁
美味冰公司
哈利·J·索恩本
财务副总裁
美味冰公司
哈利·J·索恩本
财务副总裁
美味冰公司
哈利·J·索恩本
财务副总裁
美味冰公司
哈利·J·索恩本
财务副总裁
美味冰公司
哈利·J·索恩本
财务副总裁
美味冰公司
哈利·J·索恩本
财务副总裁
美味冰公司
哈利·J·索恩本
财务副总裁
美味冰公司
哈利·J·索恩本
财务副总裁
美味冰公司
哈利·J·索恩本
财务副总裁
美味冰公司
哈利·J·索恩本
财务副总裁
美味冰公司
哈利·J·索恩本
财务副总裁
美味冰公司
哈利·J·索恩本
财务副总裁
美味冰公司
哈利·J·索恩本
财务副总裁
美味冰公司
哈利·J·索恩本
财务副总裁
美味冰公司
哈利·J·索恩本
财务副总裁
美味冰公司
哈利·J·索恩本
财务副总裁
美味冰公司
哈利·J·索恩本
财务副总裁
美味冰公司
哈利·J·索恩本
财务副总裁
美味冰公司
哈利·J·索恩本
财务副总裁
美味冰公司
哈利·J·索恩本
财务副总裁
美味冰公司
哈利·J·索恩本
财务副总裁
美味冰公司
哈利·J·索恩本
财务副总裁
美味冰公司
哈利·J·索恩本
财务副总裁
美味冰公司
哈利·J·索恩本
财务副总裁
美味冰公司
哈利·J·索恩本
财务副总裁
美味冰公司
哈利·J·索恩本
财务副总裁
美味冰公司
哈利·J·索恩本
财务副总裁
美味冰公司
哈利·J·索恩本
财务副总裁
美味冰公司
哈利·J·索恩本
财务副总裁
美味冰公司
哈利·J·索恩本
财务副总裁
美味冰公司
哈利·J·索恩本
财务副总裁
美味冰公司
哈利·J·索恩本
财务副总裁
美味冰公司
不了 谢谢 我们对现在的供应商很满意
No, thanks, we're very happy with our current supplier.
哈利·J·索恩本
财务副总裁
美味冰公司
哈利·J·索恩本
财务副总裁
美味冰公司
哈利·J·索恩本
财务副总裁
美味冰公司
哈利·J·索恩本
财务副总裁
美味冰公司
哈利·J·索恩本
财务副总裁
美味冰公司
哈利·J·索恩本
财务副总裁
美味冰公司
哈利·J·索恩本
财务副总裁
美味冰公司
我不是来向你卖冰激凌的
I'm not here to sell you ice cream.
那你想干什么
What the hell do you want?
我刚才听到了一点你们的谈话
I caught a bit of your conversation back there,
你好像遇到了财务问题
sounds like you're having financial troubles.
你管好自己的事吧
Why don't you mind your own business?
我是你公司的忠实崇拜者
I'm a great admirer of your establishment.
谢谢
Thank you.
我每周至少在你们的沃基根店吃两次午餐
I eat lunch at your Waukegan location at least twice a week.
总是人满为患
Always a fantastic crowd.
你的意思是...
Your point being...
克洛克先生 如果你不能赚大钱
Mr. Kroc, if you're not making money hand over fist,
那一定有不合理的地方
something is terribly wrong.
朱恩 麻烦调出总账本
June, grab the ledger, would you?
哈利 来我办公室吧
Come on in the office, Harry.
总结一下
So to summarize...
你的收入来源微不足道
You have a minuscule revenue stream.
没有现金储备
No cash reserves.
受合约的束缚 你如果想做些改变
And an albatross of a contract that requires you to go through
在被批准之前 还要走一个
a slow approval process to enact changes
漫长的审批流程
if they're approved at all.
但从没有过审批成功的
Which they never are.
- 我漏说什么了吗 - 差不多都总结了
- Am I missing anything? - That about sums it up.
跟我说说地产
Tell me about the land.
地 产
The... land?
地产 店面 所有这些都是怎么运营的
The land, the buildings, how that whole aspect of it works.
这很简单
Oh, pretty simple really.
加盟商找一块自己喜欢的地
Franchisee finds a piece of land he likes.
租下来 一般租二十年
Gets a lease, usually 20 years.
申请一个建筑贷款
Takes out a construction loan,
把店建起来 然后就没事了
throws up a building and off he goes.
所以是经营者自己选址
So the operator selects the site.
- 是的 - 他有所有权
- Yeah. - He picks the property?
对
Right.
你提供培训 整个系统
You provide the training, the system,
和运营方法 剩下的他们自己负责
the operational know-how, and he's responsible for the rest?
- 有问题吗 - 有大问题
- Is there a problem? - A big one.
你还没真正搞清楚自己的生意
You don't seem to realize what business you're in.
你不是在做汉堡生意
You're not in the burger business.
你是在做房地产生意
You're in the real estate business.
你不是靠从一个十五美分的汉堡中
You don't build an empire
拿1.4%的抽成来建立商业帝国的
off a 1.4 percent cut of a 15-cent hamburger.
是靠拥有汉堡店
You build it by owning the land
所在地的地产来建立的
upon which that burger is cooked.
你要做的应该是买下地产
What you ought to be doing is buying up plots of land
转手把这些地租给加盟商
then turning around and leasing said plots to franchisees
将此作为协议条件
who as a condition of their deal,
要求他们只能从你这里租赁
should be permitted to lease from you and you alone.
这对你有两个好处
This will provide you with two things.
一是稳定 首要的收入来源
One, a steady, up-front revenue stream.
第一笔钱投入地产前就要有现金流入
Money flows in before the first stake is in the ground.
二是更多的资本用来扩张
Two, greater capital for expansion.
从而促进将来进一步购买土地
Which in turn fuels further land acquisition,
进一步扩张 等等 等等
which in turn fuels further expansion and so on and so on.
地产
Land.
那正是金钱的所在 更重要的是 可控
That's where the money is. And more than that, control.
控制住加盟商
Control over the franchisee.
如果不遵守质量标准
Fail to uphold quality standards,
就取消他们的租约
you cancel their lease.
控制住麦当劳兄弟
Control over Dick and Mac.
最终结果就是 你可以把银行和加盟商
End result, you'll have the banks and the franchisees
控制在自己手里
in the palm of your hand.
如果我这么做 那两位兄弟
If I were to do this, the brothers,
他们很可能就...
they'd effectively would be...
是的
Yes.
你怎么看 雷
So, whaddaya say, Ray?
我们需要支持 我已经安排了
We'll need backing. I've arranged meetings
与投资商和金融机构的会议
with investors and financial institutions.
我们在城市中心位置
We're in the center of the town
只有这里已经过于饱和了
which is the only over-saturated aspect.
我们应该在这些地方很顺利 因为...
We should do well in this area because...
大家有人吃过麦当劳吗
Has anyone here ever eaten at McDonald's?
业务量的增长可以扩大我们的经营范围
Operation growth is going to enable us to expand.
加盟商地产公司 请问...
Franchise Realty Corporation how may I...?
加盟商地产公司
似乎有点言过其实 但其实都完全
They seem exaggerated but they're fully supported
加盟商地产公司
有数字支撑
by the numericals.
加盟商地产公司
实际上 我们宁可谨慎行事
In fact, we err on the side of caution.
加盟商地产公司
预计加盟商
与利润增长
他很保守 依我看 基于直觉
He's being conservative. Mine, based on gut,
我的直觉告诉我这些数据偏低了
and my gut tells me those numbers are low.
麦当劳正在迅速发展
McDonald's is growing quick as a hiccup.
我是 哈利·索恩本 这是...
I'm Harry Sonneborn this is...
赶快来麦当劳吧
Hurry on over to McDonald's,
我们现在在全国各地服务于家庭与社区
now serving family communities from coast to coast.
您或许离美国最受欢迎的餐馆
You're probably only minutes
只有几分钟的路程
from America's favorite restaurant.
麦当劳的快速服务最适合聚会
McDonald's fast service is the perfect answer for parties.
生日午餐
Birthday lunches!
还有随时随地的家庭用餐
And family meals anytime.
无需忙乱 无需准备碗碟
With no fuss or dishes to do.
这是美国人的食物营养价值所在
It's America's greatest food value.
难怪您会在麦当劳见到这么多邻居
No wonder you see so many of your neighbors there.
如果您不想下厨 而想拥有家庭烹饪的品质
If you want home quality cooking without the home work,
来试试麦当劳吧
try McDonald's.
寻找麦当劳的金色拱门
Look for the golden arches at McDonald's.
离家最近的餐馆
The closest thing to home.
你听说了加盟商地产公司吗
Have you heard of the Franchise Realty Corporation?
那是什么
What is it?
我不了解
I have no clue,
但很明显雷·克洛克是总裁兼首席执行官
apparently Ray Kroc is president and CEO.
你好 迪克 你好吗
Hiya, Dick, how ya doing?
如果你真想知道的话 我现在很恼火
Well, if you really want to know I'm a tad miffed.
为什么 有什么问题吗
Why? What seems to be the problem?
加盟商地产公司
Franchise Realty Corporation.
怎么了
What about it?
首先 你能告诉我这是什么吗
For starters, would you mind telling me what it is?
其实没什么
Oh, nothing really.
就是我想出来的提供租赁的服务
Just a little something I created to help provide leasing
支持我们新的加盟商
services, you know, lend support to our new franchisees.
你应该很清楚 没有说清楚之前
You know full well you can't do something like that
你不能这么做
without first clearing it.
我为什么需要说清楚
Now, why would I need to do that?
因为根据合约要求
Because as your deal plainly states,
所有的改变都要书面达成一致
any and all changes must be agreed to in writing.
如果不是改变 那就不用
Except it's not a change.
你说什么
Excuse me?
这不是改变 这是一个公司
It's not a change. It's a company.
这是它自己的独立公司
It's its own separate company.
这不在你的权限范围内
Which puts it outside your purview.
所有关于麦当劳的事都在我的权限范围内
Anything relating to McDonald's is within our purview.
迪克 让我解释给你听
Let me explain something to you, Dick.
关于餐厅内的改变 你们有充分的发言权
You boys have full say over what goes on inside the restaurants.
但是外面 上面 下面
But outside? Above? Below?
你们的权限止于门内
Your authority stops at the door.
止于地板之上
And at the floor.
好吧
Alright?
他说什么了
What's he saying?
他要买下地产
He's buying the land...
我们的地
Our land?
到地图旁边
On the map.
一定要拍到这个 要保证全部拍上
Make sure to get this, you wanna get all pins in.
确保把所有的点都拍上了
Make sure you see the pins.
太好了 真漂亮
Oh that's great. Beautiful.
坐在桌旁拍一张怎么样
How about one at the desk?
好的 坐在桌旁拍一张
Yeah. Do one at the desk.
坐在你的宝座上
On your throne.
务必对焦到这个上
Make sure you get that in focus.
笑得灿烂点 很好 很好
Big smile. Good. Good, good, good.
货到了
Delivery!
你们想放在哪里
Where do you want these?
雷
Ray!
我仔细想过了
I thought it over.
开干吧
Approved.
真的
Really?
- 谢谢 - 不 谢谢你
- Thank you! - No, thank you.
这是一个奇思妙想 而你是那个想出来的人
It's a wiz-bang idea and you're the one who thought of it.
我们很荣幸能成为你的测试市场
Well we're deeply honored to serve as your test market.
去他的吧 我将在全国进行推广
The hell with that. I'm going to roll this out nationally.
你们看最新的《餐饮业月刊》了吗
Hey, have you seen the latest copy of RBM?
刚发行的
Hot off the press.
■
麦当劳从竞争中脱颖而出
新生的汉堡专卖店正在增长中
雷 真是太好了
Oh, Ray, good for you.
麦当劳从竞争中脱颖而出
新生的汉堡专卖店正在增长中
就在离市区差不多十英里的地方
It's about ten miles south of downtown.
他们在那儿建了一座崭新的体育场
They're building a brand-new sports stadium there.
对 布卢明顿 我看到了
Yeah, Bloomington, I read about it.
将有两支专业的足球队和篮球队
We're getting a professional baseball and football team.
都在那里比赛
They'll both be playing there.
我可能已经明白你说的意思了
I think I know where you're headed with this.
一座有四万个座位的体育场 只有一箭之遥
A 40,000 seat stadium, just a stone's throw away.
想象一下人流量
Imagine the foot traffic.
一场比赛下来 一家人都饿了 想找东西吃
Hungry families looking for a bite to eat after the game.
或者比赛前 随时都行
Or before, whenever.
很对
Exactly.
琼 你的想法很大胆 对吗
Yeah, you think big, don't you, Joan?
难道不应该是这样吗
Is there any other way to?
你想不到的
Well you'd be surprised.
大多数人都没有为了追求伟大
A lot of people are afraid of taking a chance to,
去不顾一切冒险的勇气
you know, reach for greatness.
真遗憾
That's so sad.
我赞成
Yeah, I agree.
野心 正是生命的一部分
Ambition, that's the stuff of life.
那句话是怎么说的
What is that saying?
天助勇者
Fortune favors the bold.
没错
Absolutely.
看你就知道
Just look at you.
琼 你觉得我很大胆 是吗
You calling me bold, Joan?
如若是个胆小鼠辈
You don't build a restaurant empire
你也不会建成这餐饮王国
acting like a timid little mouse.
这地方发展很快
That's a fast growing area.
而且便宜 每英亩地你至少能少花百分之十五
And cheaper, you're talking fifteen percent less per acre.
我始终觉得休斯敦位置更好
Yeah, I still think Houston's a better location.
- 雷 - 怎么了
- Ray. - Yeah?
迪克在一号线上
Dick's on Line One.
你好 迪克
Hiya, Dick.
我刚接到了一个很恼人的电话
I just received a very disconcerting call.
巴迪·杰普森打来的
From Buddy Jepsen.
他是我们在萨克拉门托的加盟商
Our operator in Sacramento.
我很清楚巴迪·杰普森是谁
I'm very aware of who Buddy Jepsen is.
他告诉我他今早收到了一批货
He told me he received a shipment this morning.
已经到了啊
Oh, it arrived.
你太过分了 雷
You are way out of line, Ray.
我天 我原以为
Gee, I didn't expect that
最早也得周五才到的
to get there until Friday at the earliest.
能麻烦你解释一下为什么给我们的一位加盟商
Do you mind telling me what you're doing shipping four cases
送去了四箱速溶粉吗
of inst-a-mix to one of our operators?
听着 如果你不想赚钱 没问题
Look, if you don't want to make a profit, that's fine.
但别阻止我们赚钱啊
But don't stop the rest of us.
- 我们 - 我们
- Us? - Us.
所有人 除了你之外
As in everyone but you.
你还把那些运给了谁
Who did you send them to?
所有人 除了你
Everyone but you.
你无权这么做 你必须立刻停止
You have no right, you are to stop this instant.
听懂了吗
Is that clear?
不
Nah.
你究竟什么意思 居然说不
What the hell does that mean! Nah!
你必须遵守协议条款
You will abide by the terms of your deal!
我一直在对你受命行事
I am through taking marching orders from you.
但你的否决无穷无尽
You and your endless parade of nos.
不断在事业进步时畏畏缩缩
Constantly cowering in the face of progress.
要是你所说的事业进步指的是卖假奶昔粉
If phony powdered milkshakes is your idea of progress,
你真是完全歪曲了
you have a profound misunderstanding of what
麦当劳的核心价值
McDonald's is about!
我对麦当劳核心价值的理解
I have a far greater understanding of McDonald's
远超过你们这两个土包子
than you two yokels.
你说什么 你必须按照我们说的办
What? You will do as we say.
不
Nope.
你可是签了合同的
You have a contract!
合同这东西跟人的心一样
You know, contracts are like hearts.
注定是要破碎的
They're made to be broken.
能请你把盐递给我吗
Could you please pass the salt?
谢谢你
Thank you.
我想离婚
I want a divorce.
如果你想要平静顺利地离婚
When trying to quietly settle a divorce,
首先要问的是 她想得到什么
the first thing to ask is, what will she want?
就婚姻财产方面 她的要求
And is her request reasonable and equitable,
是否合理公正
in terms of marital property.
有一幢房子 一部汽车
There's a house, a car,
有储蓄账户 支票账户 还有保险
savings and checking accounts, insurance.
都给她吧 房子 车子 保险
Just give it to her. House, car, insurance.
那公司呢
What about the business?
免谈
Nope.
雷 你得理解 她...
Ray, you have to understand, she's...
请允许我解释一下
Let me explain something to you.
这事没得商量
That's never going to happen.
我宁可死
I would sooner die,
也不会将麦当劳的股份分给她丝毫
than give her one share of stock in McDonald's.
这没那么容易
It's not so simple.
那两兄弟是你的商业合作伙伴
The brothers are your business partners.
你签过这份合同
You signed this contract.
让这合同作废
Make it go away.
我愿意付出任何代价
And I don't care what it takes.
这可要花你一大笔钱
It's going to cost you.
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
雷
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
雷
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
雷
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
雷
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
雷
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
雷
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
雷
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
雷
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
雷
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
雷
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
雷
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
雷
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
雷
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
雷
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
雷
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
雷
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
雷
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
雷
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
雷
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
雷
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
雷
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
雷
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
雷
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
雷
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
雷
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
雷
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
雷
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
雷
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
雷
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
雷
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
雷
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
雷
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
雷
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
雷
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
雷
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
雷
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
雷
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
雷
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
雷
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
雷
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
雷
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
雷
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
雷
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
雷
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
雷
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
雷
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
雷
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
雷
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
雷
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
雷
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
雷
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
雷
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
雷
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
雷
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
雷
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
雷
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
雷
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
雷
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
雷
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
雷
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
雷
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
雷
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
雷
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
雷
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
雷
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
雷
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
雷
新口味
草莓味奶昔
说不定你们会喜欢
祝好
雷
麦当劳有限公司
我看到信纸的信头
I'm looking at a letterhead
麦当劳有限公司
赫然印着麦当劳
with the name McDonald's on it.
你能解释一下吗
You care to explain?
以前那个名称令人费解 大家不知道和麦当劳
It was confusing, people didn't even know it had anything to do
有什么关系
with McDonald's.
令人费解的应该是你凭什么
What's confusing is you calling yourself
自称麦当劳有限公司
the McDonald's corporation.
大家会以为这就是整个公司
People will think it's the whole company,
而不仅仅是个地产部门
not just the real estate arm
而我们非常怀疑 这就是你的居心所在
which we strongly suspect is what you hope.
你还用迪克的拱门作信头
You put Dick's arches on your letterhead?
这可不是你的公司 雷
This is not your company, Ray!
- 麦克... - 你听懂了没有
- Mac... - Do you understand that!
麦克 别生气啊
Mac, don't get upset.
创造高速系统的人是我们 不是你
We came up with the speedee system, not you!
是我们 你创造了什么
Us! What have you ever come up with!
你能说出一样吗 你不能
Can you name one thing? You can't!
你从没创造过 你也永远不会创造
And you never have and you never will.
因为你就是个吸血鬼 雷 你这个职业吸血鬼
Because you are a leech, Ray. You are a professional leech!
你知道我创造出什么了吗 麦克 一个概念
You know what I came up with, Mac? A concept.
我创造出了一个成功的概念
I came up with the concept of winning.
- 让我跟他说 - 你们两个小子在原地
- Let me talk to him. - While you two boys were content
沾沾自喜 甘心做一对保守的落败者
to sit back and be a couple of also-rans.
而我想要争取未来 我想要成功
I'm going to take the future. I wanna win.
想要成功 做谦谦君子好好先生毫无用处
And you don't get there by being some aw-shucks, nice-guy sap.
商场上容不下你们这样的人
There's no place in business for people like that.
商场如战场
Business is war.
狗咬狗 鼠吃鼠 不是你死就是我活
It's dog eat dog, rat eat rat.
如果我的竞争对手溺水了
If my competitor were drowning,
我会落井下石 再在他嘴里塞一根水管
I'd walk over and I'd put a hose right in his mouth.
你能做到吗
Can you say the same?
我不能 我也不想这样
I can't, nor would I want to.
所以你们只能开一家店
Hence your single location.
我们要你滚出这家公司 雷
We want you out of this company, Ray!
麦克 你觉得怎样才能实现这想法
Mac, how do you propose you do that.
我们会起诉你 不管付出什么代价
We will sue you, whatever it takes!
你极可能打赢这场官司 但你付不起这笔钱
And you'd probably win. But you can't afford to sue me.
单是诉讼费 我就能让你一败涂地
I'd bury you in court costs alone.
麦克 我是一个在全美十七个州
Mac, I'm the president and CEO
拥有地产的大公司的总裁兼首席执行官
of a major corporation with land holdings in 17 states.
你们只是在荒郊野岭开了个汉堡档
You run a burger stand in the desert.
而我是全国连锁的
I'm national.
你们就他妈是个本地佬
You're fucking local.
他是全国连锁的...
He's national...
麦克
Mac!
你有遵守饮食计划吗
Are you following your eating plan?
是的
Yes.
你有定期测血糖指数吗
And you're checking your glucose levels?
你有坚持吃药吗
Are you taking your medication on a consistent basis?
是的
Yes.
有定期散步吗 每天二十分钟
Regular walks, Twenty minutes a day.
我每天都散步
I'm on my feet all day.
有压力吗
Any stress?
好吧
Okay.
压力这方面你要多注意 这是主要因素
You need to watch that, it's a big contributing factor.
像我刚才说的 你的肾功能指数
So as I said, your kidney function
目前只有百分之五十
is currently at 50 percent.
而十八个月前 是六十五
Eighteen months ago, it was 65.
如果再下降 你很可能会得肾衰竭
Any lower, and you're at serious risk for kidney failure.
好吧 我一会再来给你检查
Okay, I'm going to check on you later.
- 谢谢 - 谢谢你
- Thanks. - Thank you.
填字游戏
本句典出亨利·朗费罗的打油诗 保罗·雷维尔的奔骑
怀着崇敬之心骑行的威廉
William who rode with revere?
有多少个字母
How many letters?
五个 第四个字母是e
Five. Fourth letter, e.
Dawes[道斯]
Dawes.
请进
Come in.
感觉好些了吗
How ya feelin'?
肯定出什么事了 我从电话里感觉到了
That must've been some spill. I felt it through the phone.
我给你带了些...
Here, I brought ya...
I brought ya some...
我放在这里
I'll set it right here.
迪克 那里有张卡片
Dick. There's a card in there.
打开看看吧
Go ahead.
- 放着就好 - 打开看看
- That's okay. - Here. Just...
我觉得你会高兴的
I think you'll be happy.
麦当劳有限公司
这是什么
What's this?
这像什么
What's it look like?
一张空白支票
A blank check.
那么这...
Then that's ahh...
这很可能就是张空白支票
That's probably what it is.
你想买什么
What are you buying?
好吧
Okay.
你很快就会恢复健康的 等你身体好点
You get better, you'll be up on your feet in no time.
我们再谈
And we'll talk.
好吗 迪克
Alright. Dick.
我们永远都不可能打败他
We will never beat him.
我们永远都摆脱不了他
We will never be rid of him.
迪克·麦当劳电话找您
Dick McDonald on the line.
你好 迪克
Hello, Dick.
二百七十万美金
2.7 million.
我们两兄弟税后各分到一百万
It's a million for each of us after taxes.
并且永远能分到百分之一的公司利润
And one percent of the company's profits in perpetuity.
太难以容忍了 这简直是在变相敲诈
That's outrageous! That's borderline extortion!
这简直就是在胡说八道 一派胡言
That's a bunch of bull shit! Bull shit!
我知道这笔数现在看起来很多...
I know it seems like a lot now...
当然多 而且在任何时候都是巨额
Yeah, that seems like a lot of money anytime.
- 而且他们还有一个要求 - 什么
- And they want one other thing. - What?
- 圣贝纳迪诺分店 - 没门
- San Bernardino. - No way.
这是送给他们老员工的礼物
It's to give to their longtime employees as a gift.
我需要圣贝纳迪诺分店的利润
I need the profits from San Bernardino
来偿清房产贷款
in order to pay off the purchase loan.
我已经就此和他们的律师详谈过了
I've spoken at length about it with their lawyers.
很不幸 这没得商量
It's unfortunately, non-negotiable.
我们的当事人完全同意你们的出售条件
Our client agrees fully with your conditions of sale,
除了一点
with one exception.
你们要求得到未来公司利润的百分之一
Your one percent cut of future corporate earnings will have to
只能以口头约定的形式执行
be carried out on a handshake basis.
是因为我的投资集团
It's my investor group.
我方目前的融资建立在无该项条款的合同之上
The financing is contingent on leaving that out of the
很不幸 如果加入本项条款 合同就会失效
contract, and unfortunately, this deal just doesn't happen,
如果加入这项条款
it doesn't get financed unless you leave that
我方就无法得到资金 因为很遗憾...
out of the contract. Because unfortunately, that's...
对于他们而言 这就是毁约
That's a deal breaker for them.
各位 你们还是能得到全部专利使用费 好吗
Look fellas, you'll get your full royalties. Alright?
我言出必行 迪克 麦克
You've got my word on that. Dick, Mac.
我们成交吧
Let's make a deal.
好的
Alright.
好了 先生们
Alright gentlemen,
请你们打开合同的第四页
if you would turn to page four of your contract.
这是第一份需要签字的文件
That's the first set of signatures to go over.
有一件事我不得不问
I just have to ask you one thing.
这件事我总无法理解
Something I've never understood.
问问看
Alright.
与你初次见面那天 我们带你参观了餐厅
That day we met, we gave you the tour.
是的 然后呢
Uh-huh. What about it?
我们把所有东西都展现给你了
We showed you everything.
整个运作系统 我们所有的商业机密
The whole system, all our secrets.
我们就像一本敞开的书
We were an open book.
但你当时为什么不直接...
So why didn't you just...
窃取创意
Steal it?
直接偷走创意 一走了之 再利用那些创意
Just grab your ideas, run off, start my own business
开创自己的事业 我很可能会失败
using all those ideas of yours. Would have failed.
你怎么知道
How do you know?
难道我是唯一参观过你们厨房的人吗
Am I the only one who got the kitchen tour?
你们肯定邀请过很多人参观过
You must've invited lots of people back there.
所以呢
And?
有多少人成功了呢
How many of them succeed?
很多人都开始经营餐馆了
Lots of people started restaurants.
但能做到像麦当劳这么大吗
As big as McDonald's?
当然不行
Of course not.
没人能够做到 也不会有人做到
No one ever has and no one ever will.
因为他们都缺乏一样东西
Because they all lack that one thing
一样能让麦当劳与众不同的东西
that makes McDonald's special.
是什么
Which is...?
连你都不知道是什么
Even you don't know what it is.
请不吝赐教
Enlighten me.
不单纯是因为这个系统 迪克
It's not just the system, Dick.
而是因为名字
It's the name.
这个华丽的名字 麦当劳
That glorious name, McDonald's.
你可以让它成为任何事物
It can be anything you want it to be.
像个大开的门 蕴藏无限可能
It's limitless, it's wide open.
发音听起来...
It sounds...
发音听起来像是...
it sounds like...
听起来像是美利坚
It sounds like America.
克洛克发音与瓦罐近似
比如和克洛克这名字相比
As compared to "Kroc".
什么瓦罐  成堆的瓦罐
What a crock. What a load of crock.
你会在一个叫克洛克的地方吃饭吗
Would you eat a place named Kroc's?
克洛克的发音像生硬别扭的斯拉夫语
Kroc's has that blunt Slavic sound.
克洛克 但是麦当劳 天啊
Kroc's. But McDonald's, oh boy.
这个发音真是绝妙
That's a beauty.
是的 名为麦当劳的家伙
Yeah, a guy named McDonald.
一辈子都不会受到欺负
He's never going to get pushed around in life.
显然不是这么一回事
That's clearly not the case.
这话说的 就像你口袋里并没有装着
So, you don't have a check for
一张写着135万美金的支票一样
$1.35 million dollars in your pocket?
后会有期 迪克
Bye, Dick.
所以如果你无法打败对手 你就收买他们
So if you can't beat 'em, buy 'em.
我记得当第一次看到
I remember the first time I saw that name
你们档口挂着那个名字的时候
stretched across your stand out there.
我就一见钟情了
It was love at first sight.
我在当时就知道 我必须要得到它
I knew right then and there, I had to have it.
- 现在实现心愿了 - 你并没有"得到"它
- And now I do. - You don't "Have" it.
你确定吗
You sure about that?
再见 迪克
Bye, Dick.
根据你们签订的合同款项
As per the terms of your agreement,
你们有权保留该餐馆实体
while you are entitled to maintain ownership of this
但是无权使用麦当劳这个名字
location, you no longer have the right to call it McDonald's,
或任何类似麦当劳的衍生名
McDonald or any such variation
以免侵犯麦当劳公司的版权
so as to confuse or infringe
该商标现已专属于麦当劳公司
upon the McDonald's trademark which is now the exclusive
是雷蒙德·A·克洛克先生名下的知识产权
intellectual property of Mr. Raymond A. Kroc.
谢谢两位先生的配合
Thank you, gentlemen.
阳光总在风雨后
It'll be alright.
现在 我很清楚你们在想什么
Now, I know what you're thinking.
为何一个五十二岁的老伯 过了知天命的年纪
How the heck does a 52-year-old, over the hill,
推销了半辈子奶昔机 可以建立一个快餐帝国
milkshake machine salesman, build a fast food empire
拥有1600家分店 横跨全美五十个州
with 1600 restaurants, in 50 states,
在海外五个国家设立门店
five foreign countries,
全年收入高达
with an annual revenue of in the neighborhood
大约七亿美金
of 700 million dollars?
只有一个词 坚持
One word, persistence.
世上没有什么能够替代
Nothing in this world can take the place
"坚持"这个词
of good ol' persistence.
才能不能
Talent won't...
有才能的不成功人士随处可见
Nothing's more common than unsuccessful men with talent.
天赋不能
Genius won't.
不被赏识的天才还少吗
Unrecognized genius is practically a cliché.
教育不能
Education won't...
世上无处不行走着受过教育的白痴
Why the world is full of educated fools.
只有坚持和果断才是力量之源
Persistence and determination alone are all powerful.
停业
■
麦当劳很快将来到圣贝纳迪诺
停业
我们专注做汉堡已经二十三年
克洛克先生 我是威尔·戴维斯
Mr. Kroc? Will Davis.
知道您将开设第一百家分店
I'd like to do a profile of you pegged to the opening
我想对您做一个专访
of your hundredth location.
当然可以 打电话给我公司
Sure. Call my office.
没问题
Sure thing.
好吧
Alright.
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
雷·克洛克
创始人
麦当劳有限公司
就是这两种核心品质
It's these core principles that enabled me to
让我在大多数人想要退休的年纪
rise to the top of the heap at a point in life
走向了人生巅峰
when most men would be thinking about retirement.
1970年
加利福尼亚州 贝弗利山庄
我和里根州长似乎在这方面有共同点
Why, we appear to have that in common, Governor Reagan.
里根 你五十五岁了才开始步入政坛
Why, you were what, 55 when you started in politics?
这让五十二岁才创业的我看上去像个毛头小子
It's why you make me look like a spring chicken.
全场一片笑声
Laugh, laugh, laugh.
看看我们 两个伊利诺伊州小子成就了伟业
Why look at us, a couple of Illinois boys made good.
只会发生在美国
Only in America.
Only in America!
我讲到哪了
Now where was I?
对 故事的开始
Ah, yes. The beginning.
那是1954年
The year was 1954,
故事开始之地
the place,
是在伊利诺伊州的德斯普兰斯
des plaines, Illinois.
车已经在门口了
Car is out front now.
我很快就下来
Be right down.
故事开始的地方
That's where it all started.
就在李街上
Right there on Lee Street.
麦当劳一号店
McDonald's number one.
麦当劳是个典型的美式英语词汇
It was a typical English-American word,
它的发音是流动的 麦当劳
it flowed. McDonald's.
我喜欢它的发音
I liked the sound of it.
它听上去很有益健康 而且原汁原味
It sounded wholesome and it sounded genuine.
我不喜欢那些
You know? Ahh, I don't like these umm...
花里胡哨的名字
Gimmick type names, you know?
什么汉堡这个 汉堡那个 那类型的名字
Burger this and burger that and all that kind of stuff.
麦当劳 它的名字就很响亮
McDonald's, it's got a nice sounding name.
朱恩·马蒂诺后来成为
麦当劳公司的合伙人之一
她也是第一位获准在纽约证券交易所
从事交易工作的女性
弗雷德·特纳后来接任
雷·克洛克之位成为董事长
他将麦当劳的业务拓展到
超过100个国家
哈利·索恩本是麦当劳公司的
第一位总裁兼首席执行官
因为与雷·克洛克产生分歧
他在1967年提出辞呈
此后再也没有在公众场合提及麦当劳
雷与琼·克洛克结为夫妻
直到雷于1984年去世
琼将他们夫妇的多数财产都捐给了慈善事业
包括给国际慈善组织救世军的十五亿美金
以及给美国国家公共电台的上亿万美金
如今麦当劳已成为
世界上最大的房地产商之一
每天喂饱全球百分之一的人口
雷的圣贝纳迪诺分店在几年内
就让麦当劳老店关门大吉
由于无法证明当时的口头约定
麦当劳兄弟毕生都未能取得专利权
如今该专利每年的价值超过一亿美金
最终 麦当劳重新在奶昔中加入了冰淇淋
校对
AdrianaK
从没有人一次性买过八台多轴奶昔搅拌机
Nobody had eight multi-mixers in one business.
翻译
Kendrick  aquaTa
所以我去登门拜访
So I went out there.
翻译
橙子小姐  Adv.
然后深受震撼
And I was amazed!
他们出售十五美分的汉堡
They were serving hamburgers for fifteen cents.
翻译
白璎  五灯炎
十美分的法式薯条 二十美分的奶昔
French fries for ten cents and milkshakes for twenty cents.
压制
山野村夫
菜单上有的基本就这几样 于是我说
And basically that was the menu, and I said,
给我各来一份
that's for me.
现在我可以下最后通牒了
Now I have ultimatums, you know.
除此之外 我希望自己有能力提出要求
Except that I'd like to be able to say that.
我花费了270万美金
I bought the agreement back from them for two million,
从他们那里买下了协议
seven hundred thousand dollars.
我得到了麦当劳这个名字和金色拱门标志
I got the name, the golden arches,
这完全是因为我工作时间够长 够勤奋
basically it was a matter of me working longer and harder than
比任何人都努力
anybody else.
如果我信仰一样事物
I'll take every resource that I have and I'll put it in
我会为其倾尽所有 甚至破产也在所不惜
and I'll go for broke if I believe in it.
除了弹钢琴之外
The only thing I could do besides play the piano,
我最擅长的就是说话 我最常说的是什么呢
was to talk. What happened to my talk?
在竞争残酷的世界 不是狗咬狗
It's not dog eat dog out there in that competitive world,
更像是鼠咬鼠
it's more like rat eat rat.
大创业家
深影字幕组
原创译制
■
关注深影字幕组
微信公众号，更
多影视资讯，等
你来发现
■
更多精彩 请登录深影论坛 shinybbs.com
深影字幕组微博 weibo.com/syfansub